
			
				<arcaneorder>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.adventuringcompanies.index.arcaneorder@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Arcane Order</name>
					<type type="string">Adventuring Company</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The Iron Kingdoms are home to many guilds and orders that
exist to promote the arcane arts and esoteric sciences. The
characters belong to one such group. They might represent
a small chapter house of a larger organization or be the sole
members of a smaller order.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Requirements:</b> Any character can belong to the company. The
company must include at least one character with the Gifted
archetype. Those with the Gifted archetype are full members
of the organization with an equal vote on decisions pertaining
to the good of the order (or chapter house). The players should
decide among themselves who the nominal leader of the group
is. Non-spellcasting characters are assumed to be guards and
skilled experts in the employ of the order.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Benefits:</b> The company begins the game with a small guild
house that includes servants' quarters, stable, kitchen, great
hall, meeting room, member bedchambers, guest rooms, an
arcane library, and an alchemical workshop.
					</p>
					<p>
					Each character created as a member of the company gains one
additional occupational skill level in Lore (Arcane) and treats it
as a career skill regardless of his careers.
					</p>
					<p>
					Each Gifted character created as a member of the company also
gains the Arcane Scholar ability (p. 157) at character creation (in
addition to any other abilities granted by his career selections).
					</p>
					<p>
					Each non-Gifted character created as a member of the company
begins with the Shield Guard ability (p. 167).
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</arcaneorder>
				
				
				<intrepidinvestigators>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.adventuringcompanies.index.intrepidinvestigators@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Intrepid Investigators</name>
					<type type="string">Adventuring Company</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The pursuit of knowledge might be its own reward but like any
pursuit, it is not earned without cost. The characters are a group
of individuals seeking a greater understanding of the mysteries
of western Immoren. They could be explorers, ghost hunters,
tomb-robbing adventurers, or perhaps an expedition from
Corvis University tasked with cataloguing the more unusual
flora and fauna of the Thornwood Forest. In the Iron Kingdoms,
many academics that spend time in the field learn their way
around a pistol or sword, but few are unwilling to hire guards
and assistants to accompany them on their sometimes-perilous
research missions.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Requirements:</b> Each member of the company must have at least
one of the following careers: Alchemist, Arcane Mechanik,
Arcanist, Aristocrat, Explorer, Investigator, Military Officer,
Priest, or Spy.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Benefits:</b> The company is able to seek funding for its
activities through support from a major university, financial
backers, or private donations. Each month the company gains
100 gc for upkeep and equipment that can be spent any way
the players see fit.
					</p>
					<p>
					Each character created as a member of the company can benefit
from the starting Intellectual archetype bonus (+1 on attack
and damage rolls while in an Intellectual character's command
range) from up to two Intellectual characters simultaneously
instead of just one.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</intrepidinvestigators>
				
				
				<lawdogs>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.adventuringcompanies.index.lawdogs@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Law Dogs</name>
					<type type="string">Adventuring Company</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The characters are professional bounty hunters who make
their livings tracking the most dangerous criminals and
army deserters. A good bounty hunter must be ready to go
anywhere the trail leads him, and so the law dogs regularly
traverse the Iron Kingdoms with little concern for national
borders or boundaries. In the end, all that matters is getting
their man.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Requirements:</b> Each member of the company must have at least
one of the following careers: Bounty Hunter, Highwayman,
Investigator, Military Officer, Ranger, or Soldier.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Benefits:</b>The characters in the company should be regularly
presented with bounty opportunities. They are regarded as solid
professionals by the various kingdoms and law enforcement
agencies throughout western Immoren.
					</p>
					<p>
					While pursuing a bounty, characters created as a member of the
company gain +2 on non-combat skill rolls directly pursuant to
capturing the target of their bounty and gain +2 on attack rolls
against their bounty.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</lawdogs>
				
				
				<mercenarycharter>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.adventuringcompanies.index.mercenarycharter@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Mercenary Charter</name>
					<type type="string">Adventuring Company</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The characters represent a recognized mercenary company and
possess a charter recognized by most nations and authorities in
the Iron Kingdoms. The characters might be in the employ of a
larger organization like the Steelheads Mercenary Company, or
they could be the only members of their charter. They have an
easier time negotiating work as sell-swords than those without
a charter and are members of a well respected if sometimes
brutish profession.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Requirements:</b>Any character can belong to the company.
The players in the group should designate one member of
the company to be the captain. The captain then designates a
lieutenant and a treasurer. Other members are sergeants.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Benefits:</b>The captain gains the Natural Leader ability whether
or not he meets the prerequisites.
					</p>
					<p>
					Additionally, each character created as a member of the
company begins with one additional occupational skill level
in one of the following skills: Animal Handling, Command,
Driving, Gambling, Interrogation, Medicine, Negotiation, or
Riding.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</mercenarycharter>
				
				
				<outlaws>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.adventuringcompanies.index.outlaws@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Outlaws</name>
					<type type="string">Adventuring Company</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					Crime does pay, but sometimes in blood. This lesson is
learned by criminals across the Iron Kingdoms, from the
streets of Five Fingers to the vicious bratyas of the Korsk
underworld to the feral gangs of the Cryxian port of
Blackwater. The characters are members of a close-knit gang
of criminals, ruffians, and thugs motivated by the promise of
coin or blood for blood's sake.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Requirements:</b>Each member of the company must have
at least one of the following careers: Alchemist, Cutthroat,
Duelist, Highwayman, Pistoleer, Rifleman, Sorcerer, Spy, or
Thief. The players in the group should designate one member
of the company to be the boss. The boss then designates an
underboss.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Benefits:</b>The company begins the game with a hideout watched
over by a network of gang affiliates who keep an eye out for
dangerous rivals and the law. When a threat is spotted, the
gang is quickly alerted. The hideout itself consists of a meeting
area, an administrative office, sleeping chambers, hidden cells,
and a number of secret exits or hidden passages.
					</p>
					<p>
					Each character created as a member of the company gains the
Gang and Language (Five Cant) abilities in addition to any
abilities granted by his careers.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</outlaws>
				
				
				<piratesofthebrokencoast>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.adventuringcompanies.index.piratesofthebrokencoast@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Pirates of the Broken Coast</name>
					<type type="string">Adventuring Company</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The characters are pirates or privateers, the ranking officers of a
small frigate. The characters might choose to be criminals of the
sea, pillaging and looting the coasts of the Iron Kingdom either
for their own purposes or even in the employ of the Cryxian
Pirate Fleet. Or they might be recognized privateers bearing
a letter of marque issued by the naval authorities of Cygnar,
Khador, or Ord.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Requirements:</b>Each member of the company must have at
least one of the following careers: Cutthroat, Explorer, Military
Officer, Pirate, or Thief. The players in the group should
designate one member of the company to be the captain. The
captain then designates a first mate.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Benefits:</b>The company begins the game with a small pirate
ship crewed by unwashed sea dogs. Known throughout the
secret coves and smugglers dens throughout the Broken Coast,
the crew can choose between dozens of safe ports to lie low or
finish repairs.
					</p>
					<p>
					The captain gains the Natural Leader ability whether or not he
meets the prerequisites.
					</p>
					<p>
					Each character created as a member of the company gains the
Hit the Deck! ability.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</piratesofthebrokencoast>
				
				<spyring>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.adventuringcompanies.index.spyring@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Spy Ring</name>
					<type type="string">Adventuring Company</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The characters in the company are intelligencers employed by a
kingdom, major organization, or private concern. They could be
members of the Cygnaran Reconnaissance Service, agents of a
noble house, or simply freelancers in the employ of the highest
bidder. In any case, they are practiced professionals in the art of
espionage and surveillance.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Requirements:</b>Each member of the company must have at least
one of the following careers: Aristocrat, Investigator, Ranger,
Spy, or Thief.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Benefits:</b>Although the characters are disavowed if captured,
they can count on material assistance from their employers.
Depending on the mission undertaken, the characters in the
company can receive specialized equipment, access to safe
houses, forged documents, uniforms, and so forth. Additionally,
they can expect to call upon the intelligence resources of their
employers before a given mission.
					</p>
					<p>
					Additionally, each character created as a member of the
company begins with either the Language ability or one
additional occupational skill level in one of the following
skills: Bribery, Climbing, Cryptography, Deception, Detection,
Disguise, Escape Artist, Etiquette, Forensic Science, Forgery,
Gambling, Interrogation, Intimidation, Jumping, Lock
Picking, Negotiation, Pickpocket, Research, Riding, Rope Use,
Seduction, Sneak, or Streetwise.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</spyring>
				
			