<armor>
		
					
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Alchemist's Apron</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">15 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">0</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">0</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">0</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							This is a heavy cloth apron that has been
extensively treated to resist heat, cold, and alchemical
corrosives. Alchemist's aprons are often worn by those working
with volatile chemicals or who handle crucibles full of molten
metal. Alchemist's aprons have become a common sight in the
foundries of the Iron Kingdoms.
							</description>
							<special type="string">+3 ARM vs blast, cold, corrosion, fire from front</special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							A character wearing this armor gains an
	additional +3 ARM against blast, cold, corrosion, and fire
	damage.
							A character wearing an alchemist's apron gains +3 ARM against
cold, corrosion, and fire damage originating in his front arc. An
alchemist's apron cannot be worn with armor.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
						
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Alchemist's Leather</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">50 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">0</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-1</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+5</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							This is a loose-fitting suit of leather armor that
	includes a heavy leather cloak and a gas mask (p. 274). Typical
	of the armor worn by the Iron Kingdom's battle alchemists, this
	armor is treated to provide maximum protection against blasts
	and alchemical agents.
							</description>
							<special type="string">+3 ARM vs blast, cold, corrosion, fire; Gasmask</special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							A character wearing this armor gains an
	additional +3 ARM against blast, cold, corrosion, and fire
	damage.
							Because this armor integrates a gas mask, a character wearing it
is also immune to gas effects but suffers -1 on sight or hearingbased
PER rolls.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
						
						
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Armored Great Coat</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">25 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">0</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-1</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+5</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							The armored great coat is popular among
combatants and adventurers across western Immoren. Made up
of layers of leather, chain, and plate, it provides protection as
well as a barrier against inclement weather.
							</description>
							<special type="string"></special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							None.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
						
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Custom Battle Armor</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">60 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">0</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-1</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+6</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							On the heavy side for light armor, battle armor is
made up of light or limited plate elements over layers of chain
and leather. Battle armor is often custom fit and manufactured
to its owner's specifications. Though this armor is expensive, it
offers improved protection and serves as a mark of distinction.
							</description>
							<special type="string">-2 DEF if not tailored</special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							A character wearing battle armor tailored to the
body of another character suffers a -2 DEF penalty.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
						
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Leather Armor</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">30 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">0</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-1</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+5</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							This is a suit of armor made primarily of hardened
or boiled leatherwork. Metal plates, studs, and elements of
chain mail are often added for additional reinforcement.
							Leather armor produced using modern manufacturing methods
is commonly available throughout the major cities of the Iron
Kingdoms. The Nyss produce particularly well-made studded
leather armor in dark and somber colorations. Less refined
versions are produced by hand throughout Immoren. Though
not as strong as metal armor, leather provides a surprising
amount of protection.
							</description>
							<special type="string"></special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							None.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>

	<recored>
							<name type="string">Chain Mail</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">75 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">0</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-2</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+7</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							This is a full suit of armor primarily made up of
chain mail. Though elements of plate or leather can be worn as
well, most of the body is covered in chain mail.
							</description>
							<special type="string"></special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							None.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
						
						
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Infantry Armor</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">85 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">0</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-2</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+7</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							Though infantry armor exists in infinite variations
throughout the various kingdom and mercenary armies, it is
essentially made up of an armored chest plate, shoulder pads,
and armored leggings over layers of leather and sometimes
chain. Cygnar's Trenchers and Long Gunners, Khador's Winter
Guard, and Rhul's Gun Corps all wear variations of this armor.
							</description>
							<special type="string"></special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							None.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
						
						
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Tailored Plate</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">130 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">0</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-1</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+7</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							This is a suit of light plate armor that usually
includes full torso protection along with armored leggings
and gauntlets over layers of more form-fitting chain mail and
leather. Sometimes this armor includes a fitted armored coat
as well. This armor is typically quite expensive because it is
tailored to the wearer. Such armor is a status symbol among
successful mercenaries, duelists, and aristocrats.
							</description>
							<special type="string">-2 DEF if not tailored</special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							A character wearing tailored plate customized
to the body of another character suffers a -2 DEF penalty.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
																		
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Full Plate</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">100 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">-1</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-3</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+8</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							This is a complete suit of all-encompassing plate
							mail. It is worn with a helmet or chain coif but could include
ample neck protection for a warrior to go without those
components. Plate armor often integrates shirts of additional
plated layers, chain mail, or leather elements for added
protection and padding. The stylized armor of the Iron Fangs
is full plate.
							</description>
							<special type="string"></special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							None.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
						
						
	<recored>
							<name type="string">Storm Knight Armor</name>
							<type type="string">Armor</type>
							<cost type="string">225 gc</cost>						
							<speedmod type="number">-2</speedmod>
							<defensemod type="number">-3</defensemod>
							<armormod type="number">+9</armormod>
							
							<description type="formattedtext">
							This is the heavy armor of Cygnar's renowned
Storm Knights. Extremely heavy plate armor is layered over
padded insulation that protects the wearer from the electrical
fury of his own weapons.
							</description>
							<special type="string">Grants Immunity: Electricity</special>			
							<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
							A character wearing Storm Knight armor gains
the Immunity: Electricity ability.
							</special_formatted>			
	</recored>
</armor>