<capacitors>					
	<record>
						<name type="string">Mechanika Housing</name>
						<type type="string">Housing</type>
						<cost type="string">Special</cost>							
						<description type="formattedtext">									
						Cost: 10 x the cost of a non-mechanikal version of the item
being housed
						The mechanika housing is the shell of the
mechanikal object. It houses the runeplate, capacitor, and other
components.
						</description>
						<fabricationreq type="string">
						Applicable Craft skill and
Mechanikal Engineering. For example, if the character is trying
to create a mechanikal pistol housing, the pertinent Craft skill
is Craft (gunsmithing).
						</fabricationreq>
						<fabricationcost type="string">
						3 x the cost of a non-mechanikal
version of the item.
						</fabricationcost>
						<fabrication type="formattedtext">
						Fabrication of a mechanikal object's housing
requires access to a mechanik's workshop.
						Once a character has the raw materials to construct the housing,
he must spend time preparing and assembling the components.
The amount of time required is equal to the amount of time
a mundane version of the item would take to craft plus an
additional week to create the mechanikal interface conduits,
capacitor seating, and reflect triggers.
						Once the character has spent the required amount of time
fabricating his device housing, the player makes a roll using
his character's INT + either his Mechanikal Engineering
skill or his pertinent Craft skill, whichever is lower, against
a target number of 15. If the roll succeeds, the character has
successfully crafted the device housing. If the roll fails, the
character can spend another week working on the housing
and then roll again.
						</fabrication>
	</record>
						
						
	<record>
						<name type="string">Alchemical Capacitor</name>
						<type type="string">Capacitor</type>
						<cost type="string">10 gc</cost>
						<poweroutput type="number">3</poweroutput>
						<lifespan type="string">1 week</lifespan>
						<description type="formattedtext">									
						This is a small alchemical battery that can be used
to power most handheld devices. The capacitor functions by
creating an alchemical reaction that generates power.
						</description>
						<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
						Though alchemical capacitors are the least
expensive mechanikal power sources available, they lose
efficacy rapidly over time whether used or not.
						Alchemical capacitors cannot be recharged.
						</special_formatted>
						<fabricationreq type="string">
						Alchemy and Mechanikal
Engineering
						</fabricationreq>
						<fabricationcost type="string">
						3 gc
						</fabricationcost>
						<fabrication type="formattedtext">
						Construction requires both an alchemist's
lab and a mechanik's workshop.
						Once a character has the raw materials to construct the
alchemical capacitor, he must spend four hours preparing and
assembling the components. At the end of this time, his player
makes an INT + Alchemy or Mechanikal Engineering roll,
whichever is lower, against a target number of 13. If the roll
succeeds, the character creates a functional capacitor. If the roll
fails, the character can make another attempt once he has spent
an additional hour reworking the capacitor.
						</fabrication>
	</record>
						
						
						
						
	<record>
						<name type="string">Arcane Turbine</name>
						<type type="string">Capacitor</type>
						<cost type="string">500 gc</cost>
						<poweroutput type="number">8</poweroutput>
						<lifespan type="string">6 hours at a time, with a steady supply of coal andwater
						</lifespan>
						<description type="formattedtext">									
						The arcane turbine is a highly efficient and
advanced generator that transforms energy from a steam engine
into arcane energy. The heart of the turbine is a complex series
of wire-coiled wheels spinning inside a thinly layered metal
lattice of arcane-sensitive alloys. This creates energy that is
carried through arcane conduits to power various mechanikal
functions, most notably the power field of warcaster armor and
peripheral steamjack systems such as sensory equipment and
reflex triggers.
						While there is variance in arcane turbines used for warcaster
armor, most include a highly efficient integrated steam
engine that provides a steady charge for up to twelve hours
of operation on a full load of coal and water. These turbines
can be set to minimal power, deactivating the power field but
maintaining range of movement, to double the operation time
and reduce smoke output. Warcaster arcane turbines integrate
cooling systems to protect the wearer from the steam engine's
heat. The arcane turbines on a steamjack are powered by steam
vents from its main steam engine and do not require separate
coal or water.
						</description>
						<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
						An arcane turbine is typically housed in a suit
of mechanikal armor, but it is not limited to powering that suit
of armor. Weapons and shields can be connected to the turbine
using arcane conduits at a cost of 10 gc per item. Changing
out an attached weapon requires ten minutes of labor and a
successful INT + Mechanikal Engineering roll against a target
number of 11.
						An arcane turbine requires 1 gc of coal per day for twelve hours
of continuous operation.
						</special_formatted>
						<fabricationreq type="string">
						Mechanikal Engineering, Inscribe
Formulae
						</fabricationreq>
						<fabricationcost type="string">
						160 gc
						</fabricationcost>
						<fabrication type="formattedtext">
						Construction requires a mechanik's
workshop.
						Once a character has the raw materials to construct the arcane
turbine, he must spend a week crafting and assembling the
components. At the end of this time, his player makes an INT
+ Mechanikal Engineering roll against a target number of 17.
If the roll succeeds, the character creates a functional arcane
turbine. If the roll fails, the character can make another attempt
once he has spent an additional day reworking the turbine.
						</fabrication>
	</record>
						

	<record>
						<name type="string">Arcanodynamic Accumulator</name>
						<type type="string">Capacitor</type>
						<cost type="string">50 gc</cost>
						<poweroutput type="number">4</poweroutput>
						<lifespan type="string">1 month</lifespan>
						<description type="formattedtext">									
						Arcanodynamic accumulators are capacitors
constructed with glass cylinders or spheres that contain steel
and gold scrolls etched with complex runes to generate an
arcane charge. They are very slow to produce but pack a great
deal of energy into a single capacitor. Accumulators can be
used to power most handheld devices. The capacitor functions
by creating an alchemical reaction that generates power.
						</description>
						<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
						The complex mechanika of an arcanodynamic
accumulator allows it to keep its charge much longer than the
alchemical capacitor.
						Arcanodynamic accumulators cannot be recharged.
						</special_formatted>
						<fabricationreq type="string">
						Craft (glasswork), Mechanikal
Engineering, Inscribe Formulae
						</fabricationreq>
						<fabricationcost type="string">
						15 gc
						</fabricationcost>
						<fabrication type="formattedtext">
						Construction requires both a mechanik's
workshop and a glassworker's workshop.
						Once a character has the raw materials to construct the
accumulator, he must spend one day preparing and assembling
the components. At the end of this time, his player makes
an INT + Craft (glasswork) or Mechanikal Engineering roll,
whichever is lower, against a target number of 13. If the roll
succeeds, the character creates a functional capacitor. If the roll
fails, the character can make another attempt once he has spent
an additional hour reworking the capacitor.
						</fabrication>
	</record>
						
						
	<record>
						<name type="string">Clockwork Capacitor</name>
						<type type="string">Capacitor</type>
						<cost type="string">80 gc</cost>
						<poweroutput type="number">3</poweroutput>
						<lifespan type="string">1 day, with the ability to be recharged as described below
						</lifespan>
						<description type="formattedtext">									
						The clockwork capacitor is an ingenious
mechanikal device that can be recharged through winding. The
Cult of Cyriss produces a vast array of these devices that can
be much more sophisticated than those commonly available
throughout the markets of the Iron Kingdoms. A clockwork
capacitor can be built in any size but has the same general
attributes regardless of size.
						</description>
						<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
						Completely recharging this capacitor requires
fifteen minutes of winding.
						</special_formatted>
						<fabricationreq type="string">
						Mechanikal Engineering, Inscribe
Formulae
						</fabricationreq>
						<fabricationcost type="string">
						20 gc
						</fabricationcost>
						<fabrication type="formattedtext">
						Construction requires a mechanik's
workshop.
						Once a character has the raw materials to construct the arcane
turbine, he must spend three days crafting and assembling the
components. At the end of this time, his player makes an INT
+ Mechanikal Engineering roll against a target number of 15. If
the roll succeeds, the character creates a functional clockwork
capacitor. If the roll fails, the character can make another
attempt once he has spent an additional four hours reworking
the capacitor.
						</fabrication>
	</record>
						
						
	<record>
						<name type="string">Storm Chamber</name>
						<type type="string">Capacitor</type>
						<cost type="string">250 gc</cost>
						<poweroutput type="number">5</poweroutput>
						<lifespan type="string">1 year</lifespan>
						<description type="formattedtext">									
						The storm chamber is a revolutionary accumulator
developed and used widely by the Cygnaran military. The
accumulator is powered by lightning generated and harnessed
within the chamber itself.
						</description>
						<special_formatted type="formattedtext">
						Any character handling an activated storm
chamber suffers a POW 12 electrical damage roll. Such power
sources are either designed to be used by individuals with
galvanic shields or integrated into the housing of mechanika
where no one can contact the accumulator.
						Storm chambers cannot be recharged.
						</special_formatted>
						<fabricationreq type="string">
						Mechanikal Engineering, Inscribe
Formulae
						</fabricationreq>
						<fabricationcost type="string">
						80 gc
						</fabricationcost>
						<fabrication type="formattedtext">
						Construction requires a mechanik's
workshop.
						Once a character has the raw materials to construct the storm
chamber, he must spend a week crafting and assembling the
components. At the end of this time, his player makes an INT +
Mechanikal Engineering roll against a target number of 16. If the
roll succeeds, the character creates a functional storm chamber.
If the roll fails, the character can make another attempt once he
has spent an additional day reworking the generator.
						</fabrication>
	</record>
						
						

</capacitors>