
			
			<alchemist>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.alchemist@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Alchemist</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Grenadier and Poison Resistance;
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 and Thrown Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Alchemy 1 and Medicine 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					50 gc, alchemist's leather, gas mask, traveling alchemist's kit, any five alchemical
grenades, and a grenadier's bandolier
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>								
				
				<abilities>					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Bomber, Brew Master, Fast Cook, Field Alchemist, Fire in the Hole!, Free Style, Grenadier,
Poison Resistance
					</parsestring>										
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Hand Weapon 2, Thrown Weapon 4, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Alchemy 4, Craft 4 (any), Forgery 2, General Skills 4, Medicine 4, Negotiation 4, Research 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>ability</class>
								<recordname>reference.connections.index.alchemicalorder@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Alchemical Order</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The alchemist is trained in the arcane
science of refining and combining rare
and exotic ingredients to create alchemical
items, including blasting power, healing
salves, and potent alchemical grenades. He
might have learned the secrets of his trade
in an apprenticeship with an organization
such as the Order of the Golden Crucible, or
he could have received his training from one
of the many freelance alchemists roaming
the Iron Kingdoms.
					</p>
					<p>
					The life of an adventuring alchemist is a
dangerous one. Sometimes an alchemist
has access to the resources of established
organizations, but at times he might need
to personally gather rare substances for
use in complex alchemical creations. This
often means venturing into the wilds in
search of rare natural reagents-many
of which are exceedingly hard to locate
or must be harvested from elusive and
dangerous creatures.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing an Alchemist:</b> The Alchemist is the
only career that can fully utilize and explore
the wonders of alchemy in the Iron Kingdoms.
An Alchemist character can augment his
alchemical skills with the acquisition of
specialist abilities like Brew Master, Fast
Cook, Field Alchemist, and Free Style. A
player should choose to play an Alchemist if
he wishes to create alchemical items, unleash volatile alchemical
compounds in battle, or utilize the field alchemy rules to mix
alchemical substances on the fly. Alchemists pair well with a wide
variety of careers and fill a variety of roles in a party, from the
Skilled Alchemist-Thief who bombs his enemies to the Gifted
Alchemist-Arcane Mechanik who supports his party with items,
spells, and the Medicine skill.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced alchemists gain even greater mastery of their
alchemical mixology and eventually can learn the Bomber ability,
granting them control over their alchemical grenades even when
they miss their intended target.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</alchemist>
			
			
			
			<arcanemechanik>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.arcanemechanik@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Arcane Mechanik</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Gifted</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Skills, and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Inscribe Formulae;
					Military Skills: Choose either Hand Weapon 1 or Rifle 1;
					Occupational Skills: Craft (gunsmithing) 1, Craft (metalworking) 1, and Mechanikal
					Engineering 1;
					Spells: Arcantrik Bolt and Polarity Shield
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					50 gc and a rune etching kit. The character also begins the game with a mechanika
weapon or suit of armor worth up to 750 gc, including the device's housing, power
source, and rune plate.
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>			
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					'Jack Marshal, Ace Commander, Arcane Engineer, Drive: Assault, Drive: Pronto,
Inscribe Formulae, Resourceful, Steamo
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Hand Weapon 2, Light Artillery 2, Rifle 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 1, Craft 4 (any specialization), Cryptography 3, General skills 4,
Mechanikal Engineering 4, Negotiation 2, Research 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>ability</class>
								<recordname>reference.connections.index.mechaniksorganization@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Mechaniks Organization</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.arcanemechanik@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Arcane Mechanik Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					Bridging the gap between machines and magic, the
arcane mechanik is an arcanist with a penchant for
mechanikal engineering. He is an innovative crafter
of mechanika devices and has the necessary skills
and knowledge to create and repair mechanika armor
and weapons or the arcane systems of steamjacks.
The arcane mechanik has likely spent some time as
an apprentice for an established arcane mechanik or
for an organization that employs them, such as the
Steam and Iron Workers Union in Cygnar.
the Iron Kingdoms.
					</p>
					<p>
					Creating mechanika is an incredibly expensive
undertaking, and arcane mechaniks often turn to
adventuring and mercenary work to fund their
endeavors. Since their skills are in high demand, an
arcane mechanik typically has little trouble finding
lucrative employment. Additionally, the wild and
unpredictable life of a freelance mercenary often
provides the perfect testing ground for many types
of mechanikal creations.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing an Arcane Mechanik:</b> The Iron Kingdoms
setting would not be the same without the wealth of
mechanikal weapons, armor, devices, and steamjacks
that shape its battles and its very way of life. No other
career has the same ties to mechanikal items as the
Arcane Mechanik. Arcane Mechaniks begin the game
with the Inscribe Formulae ability, the key to creating
the runeplates that shape the magic behind all
mechanika. In addition to their mechanika crafting
excellence, Arcane Mechaniks begin the game with
a mechanika item and have a spell list that showcases their
mechanikal affinity. Whether a mechanika-wielder, mechanikacreator,
'jack marshal, spell slinger, or all of the above, there can
be no doubting an Arcane Mechanik's mechanikal mastery.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Arcane Mechaniks become even more adept at
working with mechanika and with warjacks in particular.
They alone gain access to the potent Resourceful ability that
obsoletes the need to gain fatigue or spend focus upkeeping
spells on steamjacks under their control ever again.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</arcanemechanik>
			
			
			
			
			<arcanist>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.arcanist@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Arcanist</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Gifted</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Skills, and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Great Power;
Occupational Skills: Lore (Arcane) 1 and Research 1;
Spells: Arcane Bolt, Aura of Protection, and Light in the Darkness;
Special: A character who chooses Arcanist as one of his two starting careers gains the
Rune Reader Gifted archetype benefit (p. 115).
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Arcane Defenses, Arcane Scholar, Great Power, University Education
					</parsestring>						
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					None
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Craft 2 (any), Etiquette 2, General Skills 4, Negotiation 2, Oratory 2, Research 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>ability</class>
								<recordname>reference.connections.index.magicalorder@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Magical Order</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.arcanist@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Arcanist Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The arcanist is a trained arcane practitioner who manifests
his magic through the precise and practiced use of arcane
formulae. He might have studied under a master arcanist for
years, learning complex arcane recitations, or he could have
refined his innate magical abilities on his own, seeking out
ancient books of arcane lore to acquire more complete control
over his spells.
					</p>
					<p>
					Arcanists often join or are recruited into
established arcane organizations to gain
access to tightly guarded knowledge in
return for service to the order. The search
for forgotten lore is a strong motivator for
the arcanists of western Immoren. Many
arcanists who might prefer to study in the
safe confines of their residences grudgingly
set out to uncover these lost or forbidden
secrets. Freelance arcanists are not
uncommon, and their skills provide them
with no end of employment opportunities.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing an Arcanist:</b> The Arcanist career is
the path of a pure spellcaster with a spell
list packed with spells for offense, support,
control, and utility. Any party would be
grateful to have an Arcanist along thanks to
his Aura of Protection, an ARM-enhancing
upkeep spell that won't even crimp his
own style thanks to the Great Power ability
(which allows him to upkeep a spell for
free). It's important to note, however, that
arcanists lack all military skills and have
limited non-combat expertise outside of the
arcane arts. A starting Arcanist character is
defined as much by his other career as he
is by the Arcanist career. Pairing Arcanist
with Pistoleer, for example, creates a
character who slings spells with quick
actions and fires repeating pistol shots with his attacks. Pairing
Arcanist with another spellcasting career gives an even broader
spell list and access to additional magic-related abilities.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Arcanists benefit greatly from additional Gifted
archetype benefits and can eventually gain the Arcane Defenses
ability, granting them increased protection from their enemies'
spells once they've mastered their own.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</arcanist>
			
			
			
			<aristocrat>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.aristocrat@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Aristocrat</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Human, Starting Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Good Breeding, Language (any), and Privilege;
Connections: Connections (nobility);
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 and the choice of one other: Archery 1, Pistol 1, or Rifle 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1 and Etiquette 1;
Special: A character who chooses Aristocrat as one of his two starting careers gains 50
gc each month from his family holdings.
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					200 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Advisor, Appraise, Battle Plan: Call to Action, Expert Rider, Good Breeding, Language,
Natural Leader, Poison Resistance, Privilege, Rallying Cry, Swift Rider
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 2, Hand Weapon 3, Lance 3, Pistol 2, Rifle 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Bribery 4, Command 4, Cryptography 2, Deception 4, Etiquette 4, General Skills 4, Law 4,
Negotiation 4, Oratory 4, Seduction 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Any</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The aristocrat is descended from one of the leading houses of
the Iron Kingdoms. He could be a Kayazy merchant prince, a
Cygnaran noble, or the heir to an Ordic castellan. It's possible
that his family line stretches back to the Thousand Cities era;
some noble lines are of more recent creation. Whatever the
provenance of his name, station and prestige have provided the
aristocrat with many advantages, including formal training in
a wide variety of military and civilian skills and access to his
family's wealth and estates.
					</p>
					<p>
					The Iron Kingdoms can be a dangerous place for a nobleman.
The ancient families have many enemies, and aristocrats are
well trained by their houses to prepare them for the dangers
of the world.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing an Aristocrat:</b> The Aristocrat is a strong social career,
especially in situations where the weight of his nobility can
be brought to bear. The career also has access to training in a
broad variety of weaponry, superior equipment thanks to his
wealth, and surpassing leadership potential. An Intellectual
Aristocrat is an obvious choice and pairs well with careers like
Military Officer and Ranger due to their abilities that influence
allies within command range. That is not the only option for
a noble, however. A Mighty Aristocrat-Knight is a powerful
horseman, a Skilled Aristocrat-Duelist combines sword-andpistol
combat with high society intrigue, and a Gifted Arcane
Mechanik-Aristocrat can marshal steamjacks in a large area
while supporting them with spells.
					</p>
					<p>
					An experienced Aristocrat becomes an ever-greater social
character but also a great leader of men. His broad access to
social skills at high levels enhances the Good Breeding and
Privilege abilities while his Advisor and Rallying Cry abilities
are a testament to his leadership.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</aristocrat>
			
			
			
			
			
			<bountyhunter>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.bountyhunter@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Bounty Hunter</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Binding and Take Down;
Military Skills: Choose two of the following: Crossbow 1, Hand Weapon 1, Pistol 1, Rifle 1,
or Unarmed Combat 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1, Intimidation 1, Rope Use 1, and Tracking 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Binding, Crossbowman, Head-Butt, Language (Five Cant), Pursuit, Roll With It,
Take Down, Waylay
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Crossbow 3, Hand Weapon 2, Pistol 2, Rifle 3, Unarmed Combat 4
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Bribery 2, Deception 2, Disguise 2, General Skills 4, Interrogation 2, Law 2, Negotiation 4,
Rope Use 4, Sneak 3, Streetwise 4, Tracking 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Any</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The bounty hunter makes his living hunting criminals,
deserters, and wanted men of all stripes. He likely has a
background that emphasizes tracking, military skill, or both.
Since the occupation of bounty hunter often calls for capture
rather than killing, he should be skilled at both armed and
unarmed combat.
					</p>
					<p>
					Bounty hunters must often take work where they can get it,
and as a result range far afield and enter
dangerous and even hostile territory in
pursuit of their targets. Because of the danger
involved in the occupation, bounty hunters
might work in pairs or even teams, increasing
their chances of capturing valuable targets.
In fact, a number of prominent mercenary
companies in the Iron Kingdoms receive a
significant portion of their revenues through
bounty hunting.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Bounty Hunter:</b> Most characters
in the Iron Kingdoms Full Metal Fantasy
Roleplaying Game have a high degree of
competence when it comes to killing a man.
The Bounty Hunter is no different in that
regard, but he's one of the few who can
reliably subdue a man without killing him.
His Binding and Take Down abilities open up
whole new opportunities to an adventuring
party and introduce new ways to explore
social skills like Deception, Interrogation,
and Negotiation. Though he does not have
numerous combat-related abilities, the
Bounty Hunter has plentiful military skills
and can combine his talents with combat
careers like Rifleman as easily as he does
with more social careers like Investigator.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Bounty Hunter has plenty
of room to grow in occupational skills and
military skills but might rely on his other
career (or careers) for many of his ability
advancements. At Veteran level, the Pursuit
ability becomes essential. With Pursuit, a
Bounty Hunter is truly inescapable.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</bountyhunter>
			
			
			<cutthroat>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.cutthroat@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Cutthroat</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Anatomical Precision, Backstab, and Prowl;
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1, and the choice of one other: Crossbow 1, Thrown Weapon
1, or Unarmed Combat 1;
Occupational Skills: Intimidation 1, Sneak 1, and Streetwise 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Anatomical Precision, Backstab, Blood Spiller, Camouflage, Chain Attack: Bleed Out,
Fast Draw, Language (Five Cant), Prowl, Specialization (Assassin Blade),
Two-Weapon Fighting, Waylay
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Crossbow 2, Hand Weapon 4, Thrown Weapon 3, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					General skills 4, Interrogation 2, Sneak 4, Streetwise 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.criminal@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Criminal</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The cutthroat is an unrepentant killer who makes his living by
preying on those weaker than himself. He might have learned
his murderous trade simply surviving in the gloom-haunted
streets of Blackwater, or he could be a black-hearted assassin,
slaying targets at the behest of anyone with enough coin to
pay his fee. Regardless of where he learned the finer points of
murder, the cutthroat is skilled at stalking his victims and then
striking a fatal blow from the shadows.
					</p>
					<p>
					Cutthroats associate with those who operate outside the law,
and might band together with other nefarious rogues for a
common purpose. Typically, cutthroats prefer to earn their
livings by accepting payment for murder or by robbing the
corpses of their victims. Some cutthroats accept employment as
bodyguards or hired thugs for criminals with more wealth and
power than themselves.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Cutthroat:</b> The Cutthroat career isn't subtle in
purpose: the Cutthroat is a killer. Abilities such as Anatomical
Precision, Backstab, and Two-Weapon Fighting facilitate this
purpose, and the Camouflage and Prowl abilities allow the
Cutthroat to get in close enough for the kill. Cutthroats lend
themselves to the Skilled archetype due to the additional
attack and benefits like Ambidextrous, Feat: Untouchable,
and Sidestep. When looking for a career to support playing a
Cutthroat, Duelist, Highwayman, and Thief are all natural fits,
but don't dismiss the less obvious options. The Alchemist's
simple smoke is a great way to take advantage of Camouflage
and Prowl, and both Alchemists and Cutthroats can start with
the Thrown Weapon military skill.
					</p>
					<p>
					As they gain experience, Cutthroats stick to their strengths. The
Veteran-level abilities Blood Spiller and Chain Attack: Bleed
Out are exceptional tools for a bloodthirsty character in any
campaign.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</cutthroat>
			
			
			<duelist>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.duelist@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Duelist</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Parry and Riposte abilities;
					Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 and Pistol 1;
					Occupational Skills: Gambling 1, Intimidation 1, and Jumping 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Acrobatics, Fast Draw, Gunfighter, Parry, Precision Strike, Quick Work, Riposte,
Roll With It, Two-Weapon Fighting
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Hand Weapon 4, Pistol 4, Thrown Weapon 3, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Etiquette 2, General Skills 4, Law 2, Oratory 2, Seduction 3, Streetwise 2
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					
				</connections>
				
				<spells>					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					Possessing the requisite speed, nerve, and skill at arms, the
duelist is an expert combatant. Both blade and pistol are the
duelist's forte, and he must have superlative ability in one or
both to defeat his opponents. The type of skill necessary to
become a duelist can be acquired through innate ability and
long hours of practice.
					</p>
					<p>
					For many, the code duello is simply a way of life. Many
military officers and aristocrats turn to dueling to settle their
personal and public disputes.
Professional Llaelese and Ordic
duelists sometimes make their
living by serving as stand-ins for
various nobles who need to settle
a score with a rival yet lack the
necessary martial prowess to do
so. Duelists who continue to win
duels for their noble patrons can
earn both fame and wealth for
their endeavors. In many nations,
underground fighting circuits
offer the duelist a chance to ply
his trade. Additionally, a duelist's
skills are always in demand for
those seeking capable bodyguards
and mercenaries.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Duelist:</b> Though their
breadth of weapon knowledge does
not quite rival that of the Soldier,
Duelists hone their craft with
sword and pistol into a deadly art
form. From the start, the Duelist
career offers a unique fighting
style with the ability to weave in
and out of combat thanks to Parry
and to punish enemies for their
failed attacks with Riposte. The
Duelist career is tied more to a
lightly armored, close-in fighting
style than it is to a particular
archetype, and Gifted, Intellectual,
Mighty, or Skilled Duelists are all
viable options. Though far from
an optimized social character, the Duelist also dabbles in the
social skills Etiquette, Intimidation, Oratory, and Seduction,
making him a good choice for combat-minded players who
desire opportunities to shine in social situations.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Duelist continues to hone his deadly craft and
his unique fighting style. With the addition of the Acrobatics
ability, Veteran-level Duelists become truly impossible to tie
down in melee combat.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</duelist>
			
			
			
			<explorer>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.explorer@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Explorer</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Big Game Hunter, Language (any), Port of Call;
Connections: Connections (patron);
Military Skills: Choose one: Archery 1, Hand Weapon 1, Pistol 1, or Rifle 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1, Medicine 1, Navigation 1, and Survival 1;
Special: A character who chooses Explorer as one of his two starting careers gains 25 gc
each month from his patron for as long as he continues to explore new regions, report
back regularly, and bring his patron occasional gifts from exotic places.
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					150 gc, map case, and spyglass.
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Battle Plan: Reconnaissance, Big Game Hunter, Disease Resistance, Expert Rider,
Language, Natural Leader, Poison Resistance, Port of Call, Signal Language, Swift Rider
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 2, Crossbow 2, Hand Weapon 2, Pistol 2, Rifle 3, Thrown Weapon 2,
Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 4, Craft 2 (any),  Cryptography 2, Etiquette 2, General Skills 4, Medicine 2,
Navigation 4, Negotiation 4, Rope Use 4, Survival 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>ability</class>
								<recordname>reference.connections.index.wealthypatrons@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Wealthy Patrons</name>
					</connection01>
					<connection02>
						
						<name type="string">Isolated Tribe or People</name>
					</connection02>					
				</connections>
				
				<spells>					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The explorer is an intrepid adventurer who combines academic
knowledge and a wide range of practical skills with a smattering
of combat expertise. He might have learned the basics of combat
and scouting in a military organization, but likely has also
received instruction in the natural sciences at one of the Iron
Kingdom's major universities. He specializes in exploration and
one or more areas of academia, but the explorer's breadth of
useful skills makes him a well rounded jack-of-all-trades.
					</p>
					<p>
					Although the nations of western Immoren boast great cities and
huge swaths of settled land, there remain
large tracts of unexplored wilderness
between them. The explorer plies his trade
here, plumbing the depths of crumbling
ruins and ancient tombs for both wealth
and knowledge. A number of organizations,
such as the Department of Extraordinary
Zoology at Corvis University, employ
explorers to seek out artifacts or lore of
special interest to them.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing an Explorer:</b> The Explorer career
is broader in scope than the dedicated
Cutthroat or Rifleman. Explorers have
access to a range of military skills, a diverse
mix of abilities, and plentiful occupational
skills. The most defining element of the
Explorer is the Big Game Hunter ability.
Big Game Hunter scales with the Explorer's
Survival skill, so he can quickly gain
exceptional accuracy against wild creatures
he faces in battle. In wilderness campaigns
in particular, Explorers really get a chance to
shine thanks to their numerous survivalist
skills and abilities along with added combat
potential in the wilds. Explorers can utilize
a variety of archetypes from the Intellectual
Explorer with hyper perception who never misses a detail, to
the skilled Explorer with the Virtuoso archetype benefit who's
a crack shot with a heavy rifle.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Explorers continue their wilderness leadership
and can eventually pick up Battle Plan: Reconnaissance to
complement Natural Leader and a high command range. This
battle plan gives the explorer's party a real advantage in regions
of difficult terrain.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</explorer>
			
			
			
			
			<fellcaller>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.fellcaller@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Fell Caller</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Trollkin</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Fell Call: Signal Call and Fell Call: Sonic Blast;
Military Skills: Great Weapon 1 or Hand Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1, Fell Calling 2, Lore (Trollkin) 1, and Oratory 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Battle Plan: Call to Action, Fell Call: Cacophony, Fell Call: Call of Defiance,
Fell Call: Ground Shaker, Fell Call: Heroic Ballad, Fell Call; Reverberation,
Fell Call: Signal Call, Fell Call: Sonic Blast, Legacy of Bragg, Natural Leader
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 3, Hand Weapon 3, Thrown Weapon 3, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 4, Fell Calling 4, General Skills 4, Oratory 4, Seduction 2
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>ability</class>
								<recordname>reference.connections.index.kriel@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Kriel</name>
					</connection01>									
				</connections>
				
				<spells>					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					Fell callers are trollkin whose lineage can be traced back to the
legendary Bragg, the first of their race to harness the booming
song of the fell call. The character can lift his powerful voice
in song to urge his allies on to heroic efforts or simply batter
his foes with focused bursts of shattering sound. Fell calling is
in the character's blood, but he has probably received training
from other, more experienced trollkin with the same gift.
					</p>
					<p>
					Fell callers are respected and
valued members of trollkin kriels,
and they are a welcome presence
among trollkin warriors. The rare
fell caller that leaves his kriel
to seek fame and glory in the
wider world is likely to accept
worthy non-trollkin as traveling
companions. He doubtless expects
the same level of reckless heroism
from his comrades as he displays.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Fell Caller:</b> Like the
Alchemist career, a Fell Caller
gains access to a whole suite of
game play options unavailable to
other character types. Any party
that includes multiple trollkin
characters would really benefit
from a Fell Caller, but even a lone
descendent of Bragg can use his
voice as a powerful battlefield
asset. Fell calls are a versatile
tool that can bolster a Fell Caller's
existing combat potential or
can represent his main mode
of attack. From the Mighty Fell
Caller-Man-at-Arms to the Gifted
Fell Caller-Sorcerer, the career
offers a wealth of options. Note
that unlike spells, fell call attacks
are ranged attacks, so they cannot be used in melee combat
without penalties.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Fell Callers have plentiful abilities to increase their
fell call options and can even gain a free fell call each turn with
Legacy of Bragg. At the Veteran level, Fell Callers can learn the
impressive Ground Shaker fell call that allows them to knock
their enemies off their feet.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</fellcaller>
			
			
			<fieldmechanik>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.fieldmechanik@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Field Mechanik</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: 'Jack Marshal, Bodge, and Hit the Deck!;
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 or Pistol 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1, Craft (metalworking) 1, and Mechanikal Engineering 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					25 gc, mechanik's tool kit, and a light laborjack with up to 200gc of weapons
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					'Jack Marshal, Ace Commander, Bodge, Dodger, Drive: Ancillary Attack, Drive: Assault,
Drive: Off Road, Drive: Pronto, Hit the Deck!, Iron Sentinel, Scrounge, Steamo, Tune Up
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Hand Weapon 2, Pistol 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 3, Craft 4 (any), General Skills 4, Mechanikal Engineering 4, Negotiation 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>ability</class>
								<recordname>reference.connections.index.mechaniksorganization@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Mechaniks Organization</name>
					</connection01>									
				</connections>
				
				<spells>					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The field mechanik is a skilled engineer or a talented bodger
who, much the way a combat medic patches up wounded
soldiers to keep them fighting, can apply a quick fix to damaged
steamjacks. He might have learned his trade in the military
mechanik corps of a professional army or in a mercenary
tinkerer's workshop. Although he has basic combat training,
the field mechanik likely has experience commanding warjacks
in battle, and when given the opportunity can draw upon the
destructive abilities of these mighty machines.
					</p>
					<p>
					There isn't a nation in western Immoren that doesn't have great
need for the talents of field mechaniks. Those unwilling or
unable to find employment in the military are always welcome
in the many mercenary companies who employ aging warjacks
in constant need of vital maintenance.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Field Mechanik:</b> One of the strongest reasons a player
might choose Field Mechanik as a starting career is found in
his starting assets: Field Mechaniks start the game with a
light laborjack! While the 'Jack Marshal ability is available to
a few different careers, no one else starts
with a steamjack or has the opportunity to
learn as many Drive abilities as the Field
Mechanik. Abilities like Bodge, Scrounge,
and Steamo make it easier for a Field
Mechanik to keep his steamjack in fighting
condition, while Dodger and Hit the Deck!
allow him to avoid personal injury. A Field
Mechanik's choice of archetype and other
career can lead to entirely divergent play
styles. A Mighty Field Mechanik-Knight
can join his steamjack on the front lines,
but an Intellectual Field Mechanik-Military
Officer rarely needs to get his hands dirty,
instead enhancing others with Battle Plans
and Drives.
					</p>
					<p>
					As he gains experience, a Field Mechanik
grows rapidly in his ability to support
and repair steamjacks. Once he's achieved
Veteran status, a Field Mechanik can
learn Iron Sentinel to further enhance his
personal survival skills and Tune Up, a
quick action that allows him to coax peak
performance from a steamjack.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</fieldmechanik>
			
			
			
			<gunmage>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.gunmage@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Gun Mage</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Gifted</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Skills and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Craft Rune Shot and Fast Reload;
Military Skills: Pistol 1 or Rifle 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1 and Intimidation 1;
Spells: Rune Shot: Accuracy, Rune Shot: Brutal, and Rune Shot: Thunderbolt
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					25 gc, ammo bandolier, magelock pistol or rifle (with powder and ten rounds of
ammunition), and a rune shot casting kit
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Arcane Precision, Craft Rune Shot, Fast Draw, Fast Reload, Gunfighter, Keen Eyed
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Pistol 4, Rifle 4
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					General Skills 4, Seduction 2
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>ability</class>
								<recordname>reference.connections.index.magicalorder@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Gun Mage Order</name>
					</connection01>									
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.gunmage@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Gun Mage Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					An arcanist with a penchant for gunfighting, the gun mage
strikes down his enemies with rune-scribed bullets. Although
the gun mage has intrinsic sorcerous abilities, his skills require
very specific training. For this reason, the gun mage probably
spent at least some time as a member of an established militant
arcane order. There, he learned how to harness his power
through the barrel of a magelock pistol (most commonly) or
rifle (more rarely), unleashing spells in a hail of lead.
					</p>
					<p>
					Deadly and skilled, a freelance gun mage is a
valuable commodity who can earn substantial
coin as a gun for hire, a bodyguard, and even
as an assassin. Gun mages who served with
an arcane order typically have experience
leading men into combat and are often
recruited to serve the same role in prominent
mercenary companies.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Gun Mage:</b> Although Gun Mages
can be focusers or will weavers, they have
an arcane style all their own. In addition to a
handful of normal spells like Return Fire and
Snipe, Gun Mages have a spell list packed
with the iconic rune shot spells. As the rune
shot rules (p. 230) explain, these spells do not
require quick actions to cast, and multiple
spells can affect the same shot. This effectively
turns each round fired from a magelock pistol
or rifle into a custom-built offensive spell
with effects that vary from increased damage
to continuous effects to AOEs. The Gun Mage
career can pair with other arcane careers for
increased spellcasting options, but many Gun
Mages instead choose Duelist, Pistoleer, or
Rifleman to augment their gunplay.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Gun Mages gain a great deal
of flexibility as they pick up additional rune
shot abilities, broadening the customization
potential of each shot they take. Eventually
learning the Arcane Precision ability or True
Sight spell also gives the Gun Mage a way to
deal with stealthy enemies that are the bane
of other gunslingers.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</gunmage>
			
			
			<highwayman>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.highwayman@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Highwayman</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Ambush and Saddle Shot;
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 and choose one: Archery 1, Crossbow 1, or Pistol 1;
Occupational Skills: Animal Handling 1, Detection 1, Intimidation 1, and Riding 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc, mask, riding horse, and tack
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Ambush, Appraise, Binding, Expert Rider, Fast Draw, Fast Reload, Light Cavalry,
Prowl, Ride-By Attack, Saddle Shot, Swift Hunter, Swift Rider, Traceless Path,
Two-Weapon Fighting, Waylay
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 3, Crossbow 3, Hand Weapon 3, Pistol 3, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Bribery 2, Deception 3, Disguise 2, General Skills 4, Interrogation 2, Negotiation 4,
Rope Use 4, Seduction 4, Sneak 4, Survival 2
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>ability</class>
								<recordname>reference.connections.index.criminal@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Criminal</name>
					</connection01>									
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The highwayman makes his living robbing those traveling
western Immoren's often-dangerous roads and highways. He
could be a villainous brute or a charming brigand of marked
style and dash. Though seldom motivated by nobler intentions
than the acquisition of wealth, some highwaymen make it a
point of pride to target those most able to pay their
rough tithe. Regardless of his motivations, the
highwayman's life of crime has likely made him
a skillful rogue adept at stalking and ambushing
his targets and then quickly vanishing into the
wilderness.
					</p>
					<p>
					The character of a cloaked and hooded
highwayman atop his treasured steed is a
common subject of popular song and stories,
but not all of them are such noble figures.
Unscrupulous soldiers who have completed
their service or have been discharged because of
injury often find the life of highwayman an easy
transition to make.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Highwayman:</b> The Highwayman
career is defined by a fast striking combat style.
Whether riding down a victim or ambushing
from a concealed position, the Highwayman
excels at getting the drop on his opponents. Fast
Draw and Prowl help a Highwayman to get that
first strike, giving him many opponents to choose
from when using the opportunistic Ambush
ability. Highwayman is also a strong mounted
career, and a starting Highwayman can explore
the options of mounted combat without setting
aside substantial coin for a horse. Highwaymen
boast an expansive occupational skills list, further
increasing their versatility. Starting players can
pair the Highwayman career with a dedicated
combat career like Pistoleer for additional options
in battle, or with a more skill-based career such as
Thief for non-combat specialization.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Highwaymen can evolve in a number of directions
depending on party needs and player preference. They can
learn to subdue foes with Waylay and Binding, become light
horse experts with Light Cavalry and Expert Rider, or focus on
maneuverability with Traceless Path and Swift Hunter.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</highwayman>
			
			
			
			<investigator>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.investigator@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Investigator</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Astute and Language (any);
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 or Pistol 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1, Forensic Science 1, Interrogation 1, Law 1, Medicine 1,
and Sneak 1;
Special: A character who chooses Investigator as one of his two starting careers gains the
Hyper Perception Intellectual archetype benefit (p. 116).
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					100 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Anatomical Precision, Astute, Iron Will, Language, Prowl, Signal Language, Truth Reader
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Hand Weapon 2, Pistol 2, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Cryptography 4, Deception 4, Etiquette 2, Forensic Science 4, General Skills 4,
Interrogation 4, Law 4, Medicine 2, Negotiation 3, Research 4, Sneak 4, Streetwise 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Any</name>
					</connection01>								
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The investigator is a skilled detective
adept in the techniques of deduction,
criminology, and interrogation. He
might be a watch inspector who uses his
abilities to catch criminals and keep his
city safe, a former inquisitor, or a member
of a military intelligence-gathering
organization who ferrets out the secrets of
his nation's enemies within and without.
					</p>
					<p>
					The cities and wilds of western
Immoren conceal countless mysteries
to be uncovered. Criminal conspiracies,
ancient evils, and the plans of enemy
generals are of interest to many
individuals, and investigators have no
lack of wealthy patrons who pay them
to uncover nefarious agendas. Although
investigators often serve as inspectors
in the city watches of many large cities,
freelance investigators who perform
the same function for a fee are not
uncommon.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing an Investigator:</b> Nothing gets by
a character with the Investigator career.
The Hyper Perception benefit boosts all of
his detection rolls, and he has two chances
of success thanks to the Astute reroll.
Coupling his investigative expertise with
a varied stable of occupational skills
marks the Investigator as a remarkable
choice for social and investigative
campaigns. While not one of the top
combat careers, it's worth noting that starting as an Investigator
is a great way to play a Mighty, Skilled, or Gifted character with
some game play elements of the Intellectual archetype. A Gifted
Gun Mage-Investigator, for example, has access to gunslinging
spellcraft without sacrificing investigative expertise.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Investigators further hone their expertise in
Detection and Research, and can eventually gain the Truth
Reader ability, after which it becomes truly impossible to
deceive the Veteran Investigator.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</investigator>
			
			
			
			<ironfang>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.ironfang@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Iron Fang</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Human (Khadoran), Starting Career, and Restricted2nd Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Special: A character starting with the Iron Fang career must choose between Aristocrat,
Military Officer, Soldier, or Warcaster for his second career.;
Abilities: Fast Rearm (Blasting Pike) and Specialization (Blasting Pike);
Connections: Connections (Khadoran military);
Military Skills: Great Weapon 1 and Shield 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1 and Survival 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					25 gc, blasting pike (with a spear head and ten blasting heads), Iron Fang full plate, shield
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Defensive Line, Fast Arm (Blasting Pike), Hyper Awareness, Load Bearing,
Precision Strike, Relentless Charge, Rock Solid, Specialization (Blasting Pike), Swift Rider
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 4, Lance 4, Shield 4, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 4, General Skills 4, Survival 2
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.militarykingdomormercenary@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Khadoran Military</name>
					</connection01>								
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The character is a trained Iron Fang, and belongs or has
belonged to the mighty legions of Khador. His grueling training
and battlefield experience have made him dauntless and inured
to the hardships of battle. Skilled at formation fighting, the
character is a master of the blasting pike and with it can deal
catastrophic damage to his enemies.
					</p>
					<p>
					Although the Iron Fang legions are a close-knit
organization where most members would rather die
than leave their brothers in arms, sometimes men
do leave the legions for their own reasons. Those
who do are seldom welcomed back. All the same, a
man trained as an Iron Fang rarely wants for work.
Their martial skill makes them highly attractive to
mercenary companies across the Iron Kingdoms.
Additionally, many ex-Iron Fangs are skilled
battlefield leaders, and can be found in command of
their own mercenary units. Additionally, the legions
sometime grant leave to promising officers to settle
their own affairs, though attempting to maintain a
career as an adventurer while part of the Iron Fang
legions is all but impossible in the long term.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing an Iron Fang:</b> The Iron Fang career has far
more specific requirements than most. It requires
a specific race (human) and a s pecific c ountry o f
origin (Khador), and it also can be combined only
with a small handful of other careers at character
creation. Though their equipment is very powerful,
it is also very specific. These restrictions mark the
Iron Fang as a rigorous choice, though the archetype
selection remains wide open. The Iron Fang career
definitely falls into the "combat-focused" end of the
spectrum, though, so pair the Iron Fang career with
the Aristocrat or Military Officer career for access to
more occupational skill options if playing in a more
socially oriented campaign.
					</p>
					<p>
					From the start, Iron Fangs boast immense melee
power and can quickly gain more maneuverability
through Load Bearing and Relentless Charge. At the Veteran
level, their leadership skills come to the forefront with abilities
like Hyper Awareness and Rock Solid, both of which convey
helpful bonuses to the Iron Fang's allies.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</ironfang>
			
			<knight>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.knight@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Knight</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Human or Iosan</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Cleave and Defender;
Connections: Connections (knightly order);
Military Skills: Great Weapon 1, Hand Weapon 1, and Shield 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1, Etiquette 1, and Lore (knightly order) 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					100 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Cavalry Charge, Cleave, Combat Rider, Defender, Defensive Line, Expert Rider, Iron Will,
Load Bearing, Natural Leader, Precision Strike, Press the Attack, Relentless Charge,
Ride-By Attack, Shield Slam
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 4, Hand Weapon 4, Lance 4, Shield 4, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 4, Etiquette 2, General Skills 4, Law 2
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.knightlyorder@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Knightly Order</name>
					</connection01>								
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					Knights are proud and skilled combatants who fight for causes
greater than themselves, often dedicated to a religious order,
a sovereign, or a fellowship. The role of knights has evolved
alongside warfare in the Iron Kingdoms, but all are trained
in single combat and sworn to exacting codes of behavior. No
commander can deny their strength of arms and conviction.
A knight is skilled with the traditional weapons and armor of
his order and has received training in battlefield command and
basic diplomacy as well.
					</p>
					<p>
					The knight follows a strict moral code of conduct
that includes an overriding cause or directive.
Freelance knights or those who have left their
orders are not unknown, and these knights can
be of any moral inclination. The term robber
knight or robber baron is commonly applied
to knights who have become criminals and are
now knights in title only.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Knight:</b> The Knight career is a versatile
military career for melee-oriented characters.
Whether wielding a great weapon two-handed
or using a shield, whether mounted or on foot,
a Knight is a close-combat powerhouse. Between
Cleave and Defender, even a starting Knight has
the possibility of making three attacks in a single
round (four if he's Skilled). Knights can also
gain high armor values with minimal penalties
thanks to Load Bearing and a high Shield skill.
Remember that Cleave is tied to Great Weapons,
so weapons like the Caspian battleblade or war
hammer are excellent choices for a Knight with
shield.
					</p>
					<p>
					As a Knight gains experience, he can specialize
in mounted combat, defensive abilities, or a bit of
both. For the Veteran shield-user Knight, it's hard
to beat the combination of Shield Slam and Press
the Attack. Put together, these abilities allow a
knight to knock an opponent to the ground and
continue attacking him.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</knight>
			
			
			<magehunter>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.magehunter@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Mage Hunter</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Iosan</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Arcane Assassin and Iron Will;
Connections: Connections (Retribution of Scyrah);
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1, and either Archery 1 or Crossbow 1;
Occupational Skills: Climbing 1, Jumping 1, Sneak 1, and Tracking 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Arcane Assassin, Camouflage, Crackshot, Crossbowman, Fast Draw, Fast Reload, Iron Will,
Mage Killer, Parry, Quick Work, Shadow Magic, Traceless Path
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 4, Crossbow 4, Hand Weapon 4, Thrown Weapon 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Deception 2, Disguise 2, General Skills 4, Rope Use 3, Sneak 4, Survival 2, Tracking 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.retributionofscyrah@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Retribution of Scyrah</name>
					</connection01>								
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The mage hunter has devoted his life to hunting down and
exterminating human sorcerers and arcanists. He, like many
Iosans, believes the existence and use of human magic slowly
drains the life from the remaining Iosan goddess Scyrah and
was responsible for the disappearance of the remainder of
their missing pantheon. Although he now
likely operates with much autonomy, the
mage hunter has received training from
the Retribution of Scyrah in the deadly
techniques of that sect. He can strike with
lethal speed and accuracy, usually slaying
his target in complete silence.
					</p>
					<p>
					Mage hunters are dispatched to hunt human
spellcasters. Many of these assassins operate
in small bands, pursuing specific targets
or objectives on behalf of the Retribution,
working from safe houses scattered
throughout western Immoren. Others
choose to work unsupported, even taking up
arms alongside adventurers or mercenaries
in order to gather information or to get closer
to otherwise difficult to reach targets.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Mage Hunter:</b> The Mage Hunter
has a powerful mix of melee and ranged
aptitudes. The Arcane Assassin ability
makes the Mage Hunter a serious threat to
any character relying on arcane defenses
and to Warcasters in particular. Thanks to
Parry, it's also difficult to prevent a Mage
Hunter from reaching his intended victim.
The Mage Hunter career combines well
with a broad variety of archetypes and
other careers since it has a deep roster of
powerful abilities and a useful selection of
occupational skills to boot.
					</p>
					<p>
					Though experienced Mage Hunters have a
lot of potential growth through additional
abilities and weapon expertise, the Mage
Killer ability is the real brass ring for Veteran Mage Hunters.
It's one of the few abilities in the game that grants additional
damage dice, guaranteeing that no spellcaster is safe from the
Mage Hunter's bow or blade.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</magehunter>
			
			
			<manatarms>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.manatarms@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Man-At-Arms</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Defensive Line and Shield Guard;
Military Skills: Great Weapon 1 and Shield 1, and either Hand Weapon 1 or Pistol 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1 and Detection 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					100 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Bodyguard, Cleave, Defensive Line, Girded, Iron Will, Load Bearing, Retaliatory Strike,
Set Defense, Shield Guard, Shield Slam, Specialization (Halberd), Specialization (Spear)
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 4, Hand Weapon 3, Pistol 3, Shield 4, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 3, Craft 2 (metalworking), General Skills 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>						
						<name type="string">Employer</name>
					</connection01>								
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The man-at-arms is a highly skilled warrior who focuses on
defense as well as devastating offense. He could be an ogrun
bokur, attaching himself to an important Rhulic noble in order
to prove his worth through martial skill, or he might be a
guard, a watchman, or an aristocrat's bodyguard, defending
his station or charge with strength and steel. The man-at-arms
is accustomed to fighting with a wide variety of weapons,
and favors melee weapons with considerable reach and great
crushing or cleaving power.
					</p>
					<p>
					The man-at-arms fills an
important role in society, taking
up sword or rifle in defense of
his patrons. The Iron Kingdoms
are home to many individuals
in need of protection, whether
they're aristocrats with vicious
enemies or traveling arcanists
and merchants who require the
services of those with strong
arms and sharp blades when
traveling between cities.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Man-at-Arms:</b> The
Man-at-Arms career is a focused
martial career with vast arrays
of military skills and combat
abilities. Though the career can
be useful to players looking to
bolster their melee damage output
with Cleave and Retaliatory
Strike or increase their combat
options with Shield Slam, the real
selling point of the Man-at-Arms
is his unparalleled defensive
capability. With Defensive
Line, Girded, Set Defense, and
the potential for Shield 4, it is
tough for most enemies to break
through the stalwart armor of a
Man-at-Arms. From the Mighty
Knight-Man-at-Arms to the Gifted Man-at-Arms-Warcaster,
this defensive specialist is a valued member of any party.
					</p>
					<p>
					As he gains experience, the Man-at-Arms can quickly expand
his offensive and defensive melee capabilities. At the Veteran
level, a Man-at-Arms can take his party defense tactics to a
whole new level with Bodyguard, allowing him limitless Shield
Guard opportunities each round.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</manatarms>
			
			
			
			
			<militaryofficer>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.militaryofficer@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Military Officer</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Battle Plan: Call to Action, Natural Leader, and Team Leader;
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 and either Great Weapon 1 or Pistol 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1, Medicine 1, and Navigation 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					100 gc and officer's uniform
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					'Jack Marshal, Ace Commander, Battle Commander, Battle Plan: Call to Action,
Battle Plan: Coordinated Strike, Battle Plan: Desperate Pace, Battle Plan: Go to Ground,
Cavalry Charge, Defender, Drive: Assault, Drive: Pronto, Expert Rider, Good Breeding,
Natural Leader, Port of Call, Ride-By Attack, Saddle Shot, Signal Language, Team Leader
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 4, Hand Weapon 4, Pistol 4
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 4, Cryptography 4, Etiquette 4, General Skills 4, Interrogation 4, Law 4,
Medicine 4, Navigation 4, Oratory 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.militarykingdomormercenary@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Mercenary Company or Military</name>
					</connection01>							
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The military officer is a highly skilled tactician and leader of
men. He might be from a highly respected military family,
groomed to lead other men in battle in one of the great national
armies of the Iron Kingdoms. Conversely, he could be a downto-
earth mercenary who climbed the ranks
through many years of hard work and persistence.
Either way, the military officer is well versed in
the skills necessary to command effectively on the
battlefield, and he possesses high levels of martial
prowess in melee or at range.
					</p>
					<p>
					Most military officers learn the demands of rank
in the standing armies of western Immoren. They
must master the steely nerves required of those
who lead men in battle. Mercenary groups and
even criminal gangs are commonly led by selfstyled
captains, though few have the chops to truly
lead. Those who do can command high wages for
their skills on the field.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Military Officer:</b> When a player is
looking to create a character with strong leadership
skills and a play style to match, the Military Officer
career can't be beaten. With Natural Leader, a
Battle Plan from the very start, and plenty of room
for leadership growth, it's a perfect fit. The Team
Leader ability, which is unique to the Military
Officer, even allows him to give his feat points
to others, ensuring that the team's resources can
be brought to bear in an efficient manner. The
Military Officer also has strong social skills, the
ability to lead steamjacks in addition to men, and
the potential for top-notch mounted combat.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Military Officer can find himself
pulled in many directions at once but should focus
on his strength: leadership. His numerous battle plans and high
Command skill provide a natural path to the Veteran ability Battle
Commander, allowing him to issue a Battle Plan every round
without spending a feat point.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</militaryofficer>
			
			
			
			<pirate>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.pirate@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Pirate</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Gang, Steady, and Specialization (Cutlass);
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1, and either Pistol 1 or Thrown Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Climbing 1, Intimidation 1, Sailing 1, and Swimming 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Binding, Disease Resistance, Gang, Gunfighter, Head-Butt, Languages, Port of Call,
Quick Work, Specialization (Cutlass), Steady, Sucker!, Waylay
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Hand Weapon 3, Light Artillery 2, Pistol 3, Rifle 2, Thrown Weapon 3, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 2, Deception 3, General Skills 4, Navigation 4, Negotiation 2, Rope Use 4, Sailing 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.piratecrew@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Pirate Crew</name>
					</connection01>							
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					Privateers, buccaneers, or pirates-
their victims make no distinction-
are raiders on the high seas or rivers
of western Immoren. The pirate likely
gained his skills and reputation as a
crewmember on an infamous ship,
or he might have once been part of a
legitimate mercantile or naval force,
serving with the Mercarian League
or aboard a Cygnaran or Khadoran
warship. The pirate is a deadly closequarters
combatant, and might have
some experience with shipboard
guns and heavy artillery.
					</p>
					<p>
					Piracy is a fairly common
occupation for sailors operating
out of disreputable port cities along
the coasts of Cygnar, Ord, or the
notorious Scharde Islands. In some
cases it is a legitimate pursuit, since
many kingdoms issue letters of
marque to the captains of fighting
ships, granting these privateers leave
to hunt and capture the ships of
enemy nations or to combat pirates
preying upon merchant ships.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Pirate:</b> On the surface,
the Pirate career is a close-in fighter
with abilities and skills well suited to
the open seas. Looking a bit deeper,
however, his fighting style is one of
dirty tricks. Head-Butt allows him
to knock an opponent to the ground
while Steady ensures he'll never
fall prey to such tactics himself, Gang fighting tactics lets
pirates team up to bring down tougher opponents, and the
combination of Gunfighter and Quick Work means that his
melee kills convert into free ranged attacks even if he's still
engaged in melee. The Pirate career is sufficiently versatile that
a whole party of Pirates is entirely possible and makes for an
enjoyable theme. The Skilled Pirate-Pistoleer (a master gunner)
and the Intellectual Military Officer-Pirate (captain) are just a
few character possibilities for a pirate crew.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Pirate grows quickly in his dirty fighting style,
culminating in the Veteran ability Sucker! No longer content to
use his dirty tricks on enemies, a Pirate with Sucker! can throw
his allies into harm's way to protect himself.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</pirate>
			
			
			<pistoleer>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.pistoleer@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Pistoleer</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Fast Draw, Gunfighter, and Return Fire;
Military Skills: Pistol 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1, Intimidation 1, and Sneak 1;
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					50 gc, an ammo bandolier, and either a hand cannon (with ammunition for ten shots) or a
pair of repeating pistols (each with one ammo wheel and ammunition for ten shots)
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Chain Attack: Pin Down, Dodger, Fast Draw, Fast Reload, Gunfighter, Return Fire,
Swift Hunter, Targeteer, Two-Weapon Fighting
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Pistol 4
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Craft 4 (gunsmithing), General Skills 4, Sneak 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>										
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The pistoleer deals in lead. He is a highly skilled gunman who
relies solely on reflexes, skill, and trusty sidearm to take down his
enemies. He might have acquired this skill through long years of
practice both on and off the field, or he could have learned the
fundamentals of shooting in the military or under the tutelage
of another pistoleer. Although he might have picked up some
skill with melee weapons, his combat
abilities are focused on gunfighting.
					</p>
					<p>
					Pistoleers often make their livings
by serving as bodyguards and
guns for hire, and their skills allow
them to easily find employment as
mercenaries. Some pistoleers barter
their talents for position or the fruits
of organized crime.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Pistoleer:</b> The Pistoleer
career is the epitome of a focused
militant career. Practically devoid
of military or occupational skills
(except for general skills, of course),
the Pistoleer does one thing very,
very well: he shoots things . . . with
pistols. Since he starts with the
Gunfighter ability, a Pistoleer never
has to worry about having a backup
weapon when tied up in melee; his
pistols still get the job done. Pistoleer
characters should also strive to have
a high DEF in order to trigger their
Return Fire ability more frequently.
The two different weapon options for
a starting Pistoleer allow characters
to fire more often with lower damage
or fire less frequently but with more
punch. Pistoleers rely heavily on
their feat points for Run and Gun and
Two-Fister (see p. 221), or extra quick
actions used to reload.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Pistoleer follows the expected path of becoming
ever more versatile and deadly with his pistols. Two-Weapon
Fighting can eventually lead to the Veteran ability Chain
Attack: Pin Down. This ability allows a Pistoleer to concentrate
his fire on a particular target and drive him out of the action.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</pistoleer>
			
			
			
			<priestofmenoth>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.priestofmenoth@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Priest of Menoth</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Human, Gifted, worship of Menoth</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections, Skills and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Dispel;
					Military Skills: Great Weapon 1 or Hand Weapon 1;
					Occupational Skills: Lore (Menite faith) 1 and Oratory 1;
					Spells: Guided Blade, Ignite, and Immolation
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Choir, Dispel, Language, Natural Leader, Rallying Cry, University Education
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 3, Hand Weapon 3, Shield 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 2, Cryptography 2, Etiquette 4, General Skills 4, Law 4, Medicine 4,
Negotiation 4, Oratory 4, Research 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.religiousorganization@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Curch of Menoth</name>
					</connection01>							
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.priestofmenoth@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Priest of Menoth Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					A follower of one of the major faiths of Caen, the priest has
devoted himself to a god or gods and commands divine magic
in his deity's name. He could be a humble cleric or a militant
priest, rooting out heretics with fire and steel.
					</p>
					<p>
					The gods Morrow and Menoth receive the bulk of worship in
the Iron Kingdoms, and the state religions of nations such as
Cygnar and Khador center on the veneration of one or both
deities. Priestly orders in the Iron Kingdoms range from the
militant organizations, such as Morrow's battle chaplains and
the various martial traditions in the Protectorate of Menoth,
to those focused on healing the sick and spreading the faith to
unbelievers.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Priest:</b> The Priest career is really several careers
in one. The Priests of Menoth and Morrow presented here
represent two of the rich faiths present in the Iron Kingdoms-
the two largest faiths of western Immoren. All Priests share a
strong pool of occupational skills including the indispensible
Medicine skill and numerous social skills like Negotiation
and Oratory. Their spell lists differ dramatically, however, and
lend a unique character to each priestly order. The various
combat hymns and fiery incantations of the Menite Priest
are markedly different from the spells of healing and holy
judgment of the Morrowan Priest. Priests make a good pairing
for melee-oriented careers like Knight or can focus on a high
Arcane stat and versatile spell list by pairing with a Giftedonly
career such as Arcanist.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Priests are most defined by the new additions
to their spell options, but Natural Leader, increased
Command skill, and the Veteran ability Rallying Cry can
also make them inspiring party leaders.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</priestofmenoth>
			
			
			<priestofmorrow>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.priestofmorrow@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Priest of Morrow</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Human, Gifted, worship of Morrow</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections, Skills and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Empower;
					Military Skills: Great Weapon 1 or Hand Weapon 1;
					Occupational Skills: Lore (Morrowan faith) 1 and Medicine 1;
					Spells: Blade of Radiance, Solovin's Boon, and True Sight
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Choir, Empower, Language, Natural Leader, Rallying Cry, University Education
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 3, Hand Weapon 3, Shield 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 2, Cryptography 2, Etiquette 4, General Skills 4, Law 4, Medicine 4,
Negotiation 4, Oratory 4, Research 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.religiousorganization@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Curch of Morrow</name>
					</connection01>							
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.priestofmorrow@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Priest of Morrow Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					A follower of one of the major faiths of Caen, the priest has
devoted himself to a god or gods and commands divine magic
in his deity's name. He could be a humble cleric or a militant
priest, rooting out heretics with fire and steel.
					</p>
					<p>
					The gods Morrow and Menoth receive the bulk of worship in
the Iron Kingdoms, and the state religions of nations such as
Cygnar and Khador center on the veneration of one or both
deities. Priestly orders in the Iron Kingdoms range from the
militant organizations, such as Morrow's battle chaplains and
the various martial traditions in the Protectorate of Menoth,
to those focused on healing the sick and spreading the faith to
unbelievers.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Priest:</b> The Priest career is really several careers
in one. The Priests of Menoth and Morrow presented here
represent two of the rich faiths present in the Iron Kingdoms-
the two largest faiths of western Immoren. All Priests share a
strong pool of occupational skills including the indispensible
Medicine skill and numerous social skills like Negotiation
and Oratory. Their spell lists differ dramatically, however, and
lend a unique character to each priestly order. The various
combat hymns and fiery incantations of the Menite Priest
are markedly different from the spells of healing and holy
judgment of the Morrowan Priest. Priests make a good pairing
for melee-oriented careers like Knight or can focus on a high
Arcane stat and versatile spell list by pairing with a Giftedonly
career such as Arcanist.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Priests are most defined by the new additions
to their spell options, but Natural Leader, increased
Command skill, and the Veteran ability Rallying Cry can
also make them inspiring party leaders.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</priestofmorrow>
			
			
			<ranger>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.ranger@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Ranger</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Camouflage and Pathfinder;
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 and choose one other: Archery 1, Crossbow 1, Pistol 1, or
Rifle 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1, Sneak 1, Survival 1, and Tracking 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Battle Plan: Go to Ground, Battle Plan: Reconnaissance, Battle Plan: Shadow, Camouflage,
Disease Resistance, Fast Reload, Light Cavalry, Night Fighter, Pathfinder, Prowl,
Saddle Shot, Signal Language, Swift Hunter, Swift Rider, Traceless Path
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 4, Crossbow 3, Hand Weapon 2, Pistol 2, Rifle 4, Thrown Weapon 4,
Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 3, Craft 2 (any), Cryptography 1, General Skills 4, Medicine 3, Navigation 4,
Rope Use 4, Sneak 4, Survival 4, Tracking 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>										
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The ranger is a skilled woodsman, hunter, and
wilderness scout. He might be a member of a military
organization such as the Cygnaran Reconnaissance
Service or he could be a guide or hunter, leading
others through the dangerous wilderness for a fee.
The ranger is trained in a wide array of skills useful
for surviving in the wilderness, including significant
combat training in archery, firearms, and simple
melee weapons.
					</p>
					<p>
					Although rangers are common in the militaries of
many Iron Kingdoms nations, where they serve
as advance scouts and elite wilderness warriors,
the same skill set can be found among hunters and
freelance guides.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Ranger:</b> The Ranger career is the path of
the consummate woodsman. With the Pathfinder
ability to traverse wooded regions with ease and
the Camouflage ability to conceal him within them,
players interested in playing an outdoor survivalist
should strongly consider the Ranger career. Rangers
exemplify a solid combat career as well as a versatile
non-combat career, and they draw abilities from
a broad range of talents. Ranger play styles range
from the sniper with Night Fighter and Prowl, to the
horseman with Light Cavalry and Saddle Shot, to the
wilderness leader with Battle Plan: Go to Ground and
Battle Plan: Shadow. Such directions can inform a
player's selection of archetype and supporting career
with combinations like Skilled Rifleman, Mighty
Highwayman, and Intellectual Military Officer
supporting vastly different styles of ranger.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Ranger has no lack of options and can
begin to explore multiple different character directions.
The Veteran abilities Battle Plan: Reconnaissance
and Swift Hunter are exceptional for the guide-style
Ranger and the sniper-style Ranger respectively.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</ranger>
			
			
			<rifleman>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.rifleman@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Rifleman</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Crackshot, Dual Shot, and Marksman;
Military Skills: Rifle 1;
Occupational Skills: Climbing 1, Detection 1, and Survival 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					50 gc, ammo bandolier, and a heavy rifle or a repeating long rifle (with powder and
ammunition for ten shots)
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Crackshot, Dual Shot, Fast Reload, Marksman, Night Fighter, Return Fire, Saddle Shot,
Sniper, Swift Hunter, Targeteer
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Rifle 4
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Craft 4 (gunsmithing), General Skills 4, Survival 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>										
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The rifleman is a master of the long arm, and given the range
from which he deals death, he is among the most feared of
combatants. He could have been part of an elite military unit, or
developed his skill as a result of inborn potential and practice.
In addition to his lethal ability with a rifle, the character's skill
set can also include abilities that aid him in spotting targets and
moving into the best firing position, regardless of terrain.
					</p>
					<p>
					Riflemen who have left military service often find employment
as guns for hire, and their skills (along with the high cost of
maintaining their weapons) demand a premium fee. Others
might become involved in criminal organizations, gunning
down rivals with a sniper's ruthless accuracy.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Rifleman:</b> Much like the Pistoleer, the Rifleman
narrowly focuses on his craft to the exclusion of all others, and he
has the tools to back up his long arm mastery.
The abilities Dual Shot and Marksman are
unique to the Rifleman and essentially
provide two modes to his gunplay. He can
forfeit movement to take an additional shot
during one activation or forfeit movement
to make his shots more accurate in another.
The Crackshot and Night Fighter abilities
grant this extraordinary sniper even more
accuracy, while Fast Reload is an attractive
option for heavy rifle users who need to
perform frequent reloading. Riflemen lean
toward the Skilled archetype, although that
shouldn't constrain creative players. An
Intellectual rifleman with Feat: Flawless
Timing can operate from the fringes of a
battle, always benefitting from his own
Intellectual bonus and taking his shots at
opportune moments.
					</p>
					<p>
					An experienced Rifleman typically selects
his skill advancements from his other career
or careers, but he wants numerous Rifleman
abilities. The Veteran ability Sniper is
particularly useful for maximizing the first
shot of each turn and is a great way to deal
with heavily armored enemies.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</rifleman>
			
			
			<soldier>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.soldier@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Soldier</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Find Cover and Sentry;
Military Skills: Choose two of the following: Hand Weapon 1, Pistol 1, Crossbow 1,
Great Weapon 1, Rifle 1, Thrown Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1, Driving 1, Medicine 1, Survival 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					100 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					'Jack Marshal, Cautious Advance, Cavalry Charge, Disease Resistance, Fast Reload,
Find Cover, Grenadier, Hit the Deck!, Language, Ride-By Attack, Roll With It,
Saddle Shot, Sentry
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Crossbow 3, Great Weapon 4, Light Artillery 3, Hand Weapon 3, Pistol 3, Rifle 4, Shield 2,
Thrown Weapon 3, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 3, General Skills 4, Medicine 3, Navigation 2, Sneak 2, Survival 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.militarykingdomormercenary@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Mercenary Company or Military</name>
					</connection01>	
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The soldier is a well-rounded
fighter at home in nearly any
battlefield situation. He could
have received his training from
a mercenary company or in one
of the great national armies of
the Iron Kingdoms, honing his
talents with blades and firearms
in regimented training camps of
Cygnar or Khador. His potential
breadth of skills reflects the wide
array of military occupations
that exist in the Iron Kingdoms,
from heavy infantry armed with
halberds and greatswords to
crack teams of expert marksmen
armed with long-range rifles.
Additionally, most soldiers have
at least rudimentary training in
first aid, battlefield command, and
basic survival.
					</p>
					<p>
					Western Immoren has existed in
a state of almost constant warfare
for the last century, and there
are more ex-soldiers in the Iron
Kingdoms than those serving
actively in organized militaries.
Former soldiers find work as bodyguards, caravan guards,
or join one of hundreds of mercenary companies that exist
in nearly every major city in the Iron Kingdoms. Others, less
concerned with the law, become brigands or join criminal
organizations as hired muscle.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Soldier:</b> Though a number of careers throughout this
chapter include individuals who could be described as soldiers,
the professional soldier is, at his heart, a survivor as well as
a military man. The Soldier career boasts one of the broadest
lists of military skills but also has plentiful battlefield survival
abilities. His starting ability Find Cover can be augmented by
Hit the Deck! and Roll With It to make the Soldier exceptionally
difficult to pin down, and his unique Sentry ability allows him
to respond immediately to new threats. The Soldier career fits
smoothly with any archetype and with virtually any career
and weapon selection. When looking to build a battle-hardened
character with a strong theme from another career, it's hard to
go wrong with the Soldier.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Soldier continuously advances his combat
expertise as well as his survival-based occupational skills.
Once reaching Veteran level, most Soldiers pick up the Cautious
Advance ability, ensuring they are never out of cover and
making them the consummate survivors.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</soldier>
			
			
			
			<sorcererfire>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.sorcererfire@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Sorcerer (Fire)</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Gifted, Starting Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections, Skills and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Immunity: Fire;
					Military Skills: Choose one: Archery 1, Crossbow 1, or Hand Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1 and Survival 1;
Spells: Fire Starter, Howling Flames, Wall of Fire
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Camouflage, Dodger, Elemental Mastery, Immunity: Fire, Traceless Path
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 3, Crossbow 3, Hand Weapon 3, Thrown Weapon 2, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					General Skills 4, Sneak 3, Survival 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>										
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.sorcererfire@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Sorcerer (Fire) Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The sorcerer is a vessel for potent elemental magic. When he
awakened to this frightening gift, he found himself with
command over a primal element-fire, ice, stone, or wind. He
has likely had no formal training in the use of his magic, and
honed his abilities through painful trial and error. Sorcerers
are shunned and hunted in some parts of the Iron Kingdoms,
and his skill set might reflect the hardships he has encountered
because of his sorcerous ability. As such, he could have picked
up skills that allow him to avoid detection or escape his enemies
					</p>
					<p>
					Sorcery carries less of a stigma among non-humans, and races
such as the Nyss and trollkin view these individuals as valued
members of their communities. Human sorcerers have often
endured persecution and might be labeled witches and heretics,
particularly in remote areas.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Sorcerer:</b> Like the Priest career, the Sorcerer career
is multiple careers in one. Not only do the various elemental
forces grant a Sorcerer different spell lists, but they also grant
elemental immunities or stat increases. As far as other careers go,
an Arcanist-Sorcerer can bathe the battlefield in frost or flame,
but that's not the only option. Consider a Knight-Sorcerer of
stone: After putting another level in the Knight's Shield skill and
learning the Sorcerer's Stone Strength spell, he'll have +4 ARM
from most attacks. Due to the intrinsic variety of the sorcerous
paths, the Sorcerer career encompasses a wealth of possibilities.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Sorcerers have plenty of great spells to learn as
well as access to abilities like Camouflage and Dodger that keep
them safe from those who would hunt them down for their
questionable gifts.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</sorcererfire>
			
			
			
			<sorcererice>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.sorcererice@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Sorcerer (Ice)</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Gifted, Starting Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections, Skills and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Immunity: Cold;
					Military Skills: Choose one: Archery 1, Crossbow 1, or Hand Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1 and Survival 1;
Spells: Blizzard, Chiller, and Ice Bolt
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Camouflage, Dodger, Elemental Mastery, Immunity: Cold, Traceless Path
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 3, Crossbow 3, Hand Weapon 3, Thrown Weapon 2, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					General Skills 4, Sneak 3, Survival 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>										
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.sorcererice@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Sorcerer (Ice) Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The sorcerer is a vessel for potent elemental magic. When he
awakened to this frightening gift, he found himself with
command over a primal element-fire, ice, stone, or wind. He
has likely had no formal training in the use of his magic, and
honed his abilities through painful trial and error. Sorcerers
are shunned and hunted in some parts of the Iron Kingdoms,
and his skill set might reflect the hardships he has encountered
because of his sorcerous ability. As such, he could have picked
up skills that allow him to avoid detection or escape his enemies
					</p>
					<p>
					Sorcery carries less of a stigma among non-humans, and races
such as the Nyss and trollkin view these individuals as valued
members of their communities. Human sorcerers have often
endured persecution and might be labeled witches and heretics,
particularly in remote areas.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Sorcerer:</b> Like the Priest career, the Sorcerer career
is multiple careers in one. Not only do the various elemental
forces grant a Sorcerer different spell lists, but they also grant
elemental immunities or stat increases. As far as other careers go,
an Arcanist-Sorcerer can bathe the battlefield in frost or flame,
but that's not the only option. Consider a Knight-Sorcerer of
stone: After putting another level in the Knight's Shield skill and
learning the Sorcerer's Stone Strength spell, he'll have +4 ARM
from most attacks. Due to the intrinsic variety of the sorcerous
paths, the Sorcerer career encompasses a wealth of possibilities.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Sorcerers have plenty of great spells to learn as
well as access to abilities like Camouflage and Dodger that keep
them safe from those who would hunt them down for their
questionable gifts.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</sorcererice>
			
			
			<sorcererstone>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.sorcererstone@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Sorcerer (Stone)</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Gifted, Starting Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections, Skills and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Special: Stone sorcerers begin with +1 PHY and +1 to their racial
maximum PHY at each level.;
					Military Skills: Choose one: Archery 1, Crossbow 1, or Hand Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1 and Survival 1;
Spells: Battering Ram, Solid Ground, and Stone Stance
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Camouflage, Dodger, Elemental Mastery, Traceless Path
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 3, Crossbow 3, Hand Weapon 3, Thrown Weapon 2, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					General Skills 4, Sneak 3, Survival 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>										
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.sorcererstone@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Sorcerer (Stone) Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The sorcerer is a vessel for potent elemental magic. When he
awakened to this frightening gift, he found himself with
command over a primal element-fire, ice, stone, or wind. He
has likely had no formal training in the use of his magic, and
honed his abilities through painful trial and error. Sorcerers
are shunned and hunted in some parts of the Iron Kingdoms,
and his skill set might reflect the hardships he has encountered
because of his sorcerous ability. As such, he could have picked
up skills that allow him to avoid detection or escape his enemies
					</p>
					<p>
					Sorcery carries less of a stigma among non-humans, and races
such as the Nyss and trollkin view these individuals as valued
members of their communities. Human sorcerers have often
endured persecution and might be labeled witches and heretics,
particularly in remote areas.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Sorcerer:</b> Like the Priest career, the Sorcerer career
is multiple careers in one. Not only do the various elemental
forces grant a Sorcerer different spell lists, but they also grant
elemental immunities or stat increases. As far as other careers go,
an Arcanist-Sorcerer can bathe the battlefield in frost or flame,
but that's not the only option. Consider a Knight-Sorcerer of
stone: After putting another level in the Knight's Shield skill and
learning the Sorcerer's Stone Strength spell, he'll have +4 ARM
from most attacks. Due to the intrinsic variety of the sorcerous
paths, the Sorcerer career encompasses a wealth of possibilities.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Sorcerers have plenty of great spells to learn as
well as access to abilities like Camouflage and Dodger that keep
them safe from those who would hunt them down for their
questionable gifts.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</sorcererstone>
			
			
			
			<sorcererstorm>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.sorcererstorm@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Sorcerer (Storm)</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Gifted, Starting Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections, Skills and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Special: Storm sorcerers begin with +1 SPD and +1 to their racial maximum SPD
at each level.;
					Military Skills: Choose one: Archery 1, Crossbow 1, or Hand Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Detection 1 and Survival 1;
Spells: Razor Wind, Storm Tossed, and Wind Blast
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Camouflage, Dodger, Elemental Mastery, Traceless Path
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Archery 3, Crossbow 3, Hand Weapon 3, Thrown Weapon 2, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					General Skills 4, Sneak 3, Survival 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>										
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.sorcererstorm@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Sorcerer (Storm) Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The sorcerer is a vessel for potent elemental magic. When he
awakened to this frightening gift, he found himself with
command over a primal element-fire, ice, stone, or wind. He
has likely had no formal training in the use of his magic, and
honed his abilities through painful trial and error. Sorcerers
are shunned and hunted in some parts of the Iron Kingdoms,
and his skill set might reflect the hardships he has encountered
because of his sorcerous ability. As such, he could have picked
up skills that allow him to avoid detection or escape his enemies
					</p>
					<p>
					Sorcery carries less of a stigma among non-humans, and races
such as the Nyss and trollkin view these individuals as valued
members of their communities. Human sorcerers have often
endured persecution and might be labeled witches and heretics,
particularly in remote areas.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Sorcerer:</b> Like the Priest career, the Sorcerer career
is multiple careers in one. Not only do the various elemental
forces grant a Sorcerer different spell lists, but they also grant
elemental immunities or stat increases. As far as other careers go,
an Arcanist-Sorcerer can bathe the battlefield in frost or flame,
but that's not the only option. Consider a Knight-Sorcerer of
stone: After putting another level in the Knight's Shield skill and
learning the Sorcerer's Stone Strength spell, he'll have +4 ARM
from most attacks. Due to the intrinsic variety of the sorcerous
paths, the Sorcerer career encompasses a wealth of possibilities.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Sorcerers have plenty of great spells to learn as
well as access to abilities like Camouflage and Dodger that keep
them safe from those who would hunt them down for their
questionable gifts.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</sorcererstorm>
			
			
			<spy>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.spy@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Spy</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Battle Plan: Shadow, Cover Identity, and Language (choose one);
Connections: Connections (intelligence network);
Military Skills: Choose one: Hand Weapon 1, Pistol 1, or Thrown Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1, Deception 1, Detection 1, Disguise 1, and Sneak 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					100 gc and forged identity papers
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Battle Plan: Shadow, Cover Identity, Iron Will, Language, Poison Resistance, Prowl,
Signal Language, Truth Reader, Waylay
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Hand Weapon 3, Pistol 3, Thrown Weapon 3, Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Bribery 4, Command 3, Cryptography 4, Deception 4, Disguise 4, Escape Artist 4,
Etiquette 4, Forgery 4, General Skills 4, Interrogation 4, Law 4, Lock Picking 2,
Negotiation 4, Seduction 4, Sneak 4, Streetwise 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Any</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The spy is an intelligencer, either a freelance operative or an
agent of one of the Iron Kingdoms. He lives in a shady world
of hidden truths and shifting alliances. His skill set includes
numerous ways to gain information his nation or clients
require, and he might be a master of diplomacy,
skilled at seduction, well versed in brutal interrogation
techniques, or all three. The spy is a fairly skilled
combatant, as well, with the ability to fight his way out
of situations he cannot avoid through other means.
					</p>
					<p>
					In the Iron Kingdoms, nearly every nation and
influential organization employs spies and intelligence
gathering agents. Examples include the Cygnaran
Reconnaissance Service, King Baird's network of
informants in Ord, the Greylords Prikaz Chancellery in
Khador, and groups such as Dargule's Mice that gather
information for the Sancteum. Freelance groups, such
as the mysterious Unseen Hand, work for anyone with
the coin to pay for their services. Such groups offer
a variety of covert services, from simple research to
intelligence gathering by more direct means.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Spy:</b> The Spy career has a very distinct role,
so it might not be an optimal fit in every campaign
type. In campaigns laden with intrigue, subterfuge,
and investigation, the Spy's strengths really come
to light. Spies have a truly impressive array of noncombat
skills and can even gain a degree of competence
with other skills thanks to Cover Identity. The free
occupational skill from Cover Identity allows a Spy to
better assist his allies with Medicine or even to dabble
in rudimentary Alchemy. Paired with a strong combat
career, a Spy can become a very well-rounded character
with plenty of opportunities during narrative and
combat encounters alike.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Spy has plenty of room for growth throughout
his occupational skills and can eventually learn the Truth
Reader ability. No matter how far he comes, there's also always
room for another Cover Identity.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</spy>
			
			
			<stormblade>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.stormblade@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Stormblade</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Human (Cygnaran), Starting Career, and Restricted2nd Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Special: A character starting with the Stormblade career must choose between Aristocrat,
Knight, Man-at-Arms, Military Officer, Soldier, or Warcaster for his second career.;
Abilities: Blaster and Specialization (Storm Glaive);
Connections: Connections (Cygnaran military);
Military Skills: Great Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1, Detection 1, Etiquette 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					Storm Glaive and Storm Knight armor
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					'Jack Marshal, Blaster, Close Shot, Load Bearing, Quick Work, Relentless Charge,
Specialization (Storm Glaive)
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 4
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 4, Etiquette 2, General Skills 4, Medicine 2
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.militarykingdomormercenary@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Cygnaran Military</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The character is a knight of Cygnar chosen to serve in the elite
fighting force known as the Stormblades. He combines ancient
fighting traditions with state-of-the-art mechanikal weaponry,
lighting up the battlefield with blasts of arcing electricity
from his signature weapon, the Storm Glaive. In addition to
his fighting skills, the Stormblade is also trained in battlefield
command and the etiquette expected of a knight.
					</p>
					<p>
					Stormblades fight for the armies of Cygnar but are, on occasion,
given special dispensation to take leave of their brothers and
pursue the interests of the crown elsewhere. In such instances, a
Stormblade might seek out others skilled individuals to aid him
on his quest. Stormblades also sometimes retire from the order
completely to pursue their own interests. These individuals
retain a host of useful battlefield skills and sometimes manage
to hold on to their Storm Glaives.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Stormblade:</b> The Stormblade is a specific a nd
highly specialized career. He is a galvanic knight of
Cygnar who wields the iconic storm glaive and wears
heavy, electrically insulated armor. Stormblades are
peerless with the powerful storm glaives, and their armor
protects them from the shocks the weapons typically
deliver to their wielders. A starting Stormblade's
other career shapes his development. The Aristocrat-
Stormblade is comfortable at court from Ceryl to Caspia,
while the Man-at-Arms-Stormblade bravely fights to
protect his allies.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Stormblade becomes more comfortable
in his armor and can eventually learn to use the glaive's
electrical blast after felling an enemy in melee combat.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</stormblade>
			
			
			
			<thief>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.thief@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Thief</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">None</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Conniver and Dodger;
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 or Thrown Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Bribery 1, Deception 1, Escape Artist 1, Lock Picking 2, Pickpocket 2,
Sneak 1, and Streetwise 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					75 gc and thief's tools
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Appraise, Camouflage, Card Sharp, Conniver, Dodger, Fleet Foot, Get Away,
Language (Five Cant), Parry, Prowl, Traceless Path
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Hand Weapon 3, Pistol 2, Thrown Weapon 3, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Bribery 4, Craft 2 (any), Deception 4, Disguise 4, Escape Artist 4, Etiquette 1, Forgery 4,
General Skills 4, Law 2, Lock Picking 4, Negotiation 4, Pickpocket 4, Sneak 4, Streetwise 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.criminal@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Criminal</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The thief is a skilled criminal adept at breaking and entering,
pickpocketing, and any number of skills designed to relieve a
target of his coin and valuables. The thief might be a member of
an organized group, such as the criminal syndicates operating
out of Five Fingers, or he could be a lone burglar, cutpurse,
or con artist, hoarding his ill-gotten proceeds for himself.
Although his focus lies elsewhere, the thief is likely skilled in
the use of one or more easily concealable weapons.
					</p>
					<p>
					Where there is wealth, there are thieves, and such rogues are
common in all major cities in the Iron Kingdoms. Obviously,
the more lawless the city, the greater the number of criminals,
and many of the more prosperous thieves operate in areas such
as war-torn Llael, Ord, and amid the crowded streets of Cygnar
and Khador's great cities.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Thief:</b> The Thief is
one shady customer, and the
Thief career is ideal for criminal
characters. Whether he's a
pickpocket, gambler, safecracker,
forger, con artist, or enforcer,
the thief has his criminal bases
covered. The Thief's abilities
reinforce his slippery nature with over half of the career abilities
in some way helping him hide, dodge, escape, or otherwise
evade threats he faces. This is not to say the Thief cannot hold
his own in a fight, although a more offensively minded career
helps him in such pursuits. Though there's nothing wrong with
a Mighty, Intellectual, or Gifted Thief, the Skilled Thief is by far
the most common thanks to archetype benefits such as Deft,
Feat: Untouchable, and Preternatural Awareness.
					</p>
					<p>
					The experienced Thief can hone his criminal skills as well as
his ability to get away with it. The unique Veteran ability Get
Away is worth particular mention, since it allows the speedy
rogue to advance his full SPD when he dodges instead of
advancing 2".
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</thief>
			
			
			<trencher>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.trencher@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Trencher</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Human, Ogrun, or Trollkin (Cygnaran), Starting Career, and Restricted2nd Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections and Skills</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Special: A character starting with the Trencher career must choose between Military
Officer, Ranger, Rifleman, Soldier, or Warcaster for his second career.;
Abilities: Bayonet Charge and Dig In;
Connections: Connections (Cygnaran military);
Military Skills: Great Weapon 1, Rifle 1, Thrown Weapon 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1 and Detection 1
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					25 gc, ammo bandolier, bayonet, entrenching spade, military rifle, 3 smoke grenades, and
Trencher medium infantry armor
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					'Jack Marshal, Anatomical Precision, Bayonet Charge, Bomber, Dig In, Fire in the Hole!,
Grenadier, Hit the Deck!, Relentless Charge, Specialization (Bayonet)
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 3, Light Artillery 4, Hand Weapon 3, Pistol 3, Rifle 4, Thrown Weapon 4,
Unarmed Combat 3
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 3, General Skills 4, Interrogation 3, Medicine 3, Sneak 3, Survival 3
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.militarykingdomormercenary@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Cygnaran Military</name>
					</connection01>
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					Trenchers are the hardy soldiers that form the backbone of the
Cygnaran military. Sometimes called "grave diggers," they
are the first Cygnarans onto the battlefield and often the last
to leave. Especially trained for trench-to-trench fighting, these
soldiers carry out numerous battlefield roles. The character
might be a simple infantryman, trained in the rifle and bayonet,
or he could have been part of a heavy weapons crew with the
skills necessary to fire and maintain cannons and chain guns.
The character has likely received training in other skills useful
in combat, such as basic interrogation techniques, first aid, and
wilderness survival.
					</p>
					<p>
					It is not uncommon for Trenchers to become mercenaries once
they leave the Cygnaran military. The skills learned on the
battlefields of western Immoren are easily parleyed into
sometimes lucrative positions in the more prominent
mercenary companies, especially for Trenchers who
received training in heavy weapons or learned
the necessary skills to commanded warjacks
in the field.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Trencher:</b> Though not
nearly as restrictive as the Iron Fang or
Stormblade, the Trencher career is still
far more focused than most when it comes
to race, nationality, and starting career options. Of
particular note is the fact that regardless of the other career,
the Trencher is a predominantly combat character with fewer
options in an investigative campaign or campaign of high
intrigue. But when it comes to combat, a Trencher is a versatile
character with numerous military skills and combat-related
abilities. Skilled with rifle, bayonet, and grenades, a Trencher
has several paths available to him from the Rifleman-Trencher's
ranged expertise to the Trencher-Warcaster who charges into
the heat of battle.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Trenchers continue on the path of combat
survivalists or snipers but can also become real experts with
grenades. The Veteran Bomber ability can join Fire in the Hole!
and Grenadier leading to a real expert in maximizing the
potential of explosives.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</trencher>
			
			
			<warcaster>
				<listlink type="windowreference">
						<class>referencecareer</class>
						<recordname>reference.careers.index.warcaster@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
				</listlink>
				
				<name type="string">Warcaster</name>
				<prerequisites type="string">Gifted (Focuser tradition), Starting Career</prerequisites>
				
				<startingtable>
					<header type="string">Starting Abilities, Connections, Skills and Spells</header>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Abilities: Bond;
Military Skills: Hand Weapon 1 and Pistol 1;
Occupational Skills: Command 1 and Detection 1;
Spells: Boundless Charge and Convection;
Special: Change the character's arcane tradition to focuser if he has another arcane
career. A warcaster can boost only with mechanikal weapons they have bonded to.
					</parsestring>
					<assetsstring type="string">
					Choose one of the following: suit of warcaster armor (light or medium), mechanika
hand weapon, or a mechanika hand cannon (with ten rounds of ammunition).
Mechanika weapons have housings of the chosen weapon, runeplates inscribed with
the Bond rune, and are powered by alchemical capacitors. This item begins the game
bonded to the warcaster.
					</assetsstring>
				</startingtable>		
				
				<abilities>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Bond, Field Marshal: Magical Attack, Field Marshal: Relentless Charge, Field Marshal:
Shield Guard, Natural Leader
					</parsestring>	
				</abilities>
				
				<militaryskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Great Weapon 3, Hand Weapon 3, Pistol 3, Unarmed Combat 2
					</parsestring>										
				</militaryskills>
				
				<occupationalskills>
					
					<parsestring type="string">
					Command 4, General Skills 4
					</parsestring>										
				</occupationalskills>
				
				<connections>
					<connection01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.militarykingdomormercenary@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>					
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Mercenary Company or Military</name>
					</connection01>						
				</connections>
				
				<spells>
					<list01>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
								<class>referencespellslist</class>
								<recordname>reference.spells.lists.index.warcaster@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>								
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Warcaster Spell List</name>
					</list01>
				</spells>
				
				
				<text type="formattedtext">										
					<p>
					The warcaster is a rare and powerful battle mage gifted with the
ability to commune with and command the most devastating
weapons of war in the Iron Kingdoms: warjacks. The character's
ability to manipulate the forces of magic is intrinsic, but it is
likely he learned to hone and shape it in one of the great military
institutes responsible for warcaster training-such as Cygnar's
Strategic Academy-or as an apprentice to a warcaster. The
character is a mighty force on the battlefield and commands a
versatile set of combat skills as well as lethal spells.
					</p>
					<p>
					The military potency of each nation in the Iron Kingdoms
is dependent on the strength and number of its warcasters
to maintain power and fend of rivals. As such, nearly all
warcasters have at some point served in the military. Freelance
warcasters can be found among some of the greatest mercenary
companies in western Immoren. Many of these free companies
are led by one or more powerful warcasters. Those warcasters
who eschew the discipline of employment in a standing army
might be hampered by lessened access to the infrastructure
necessary to maintain a stable of warjacks but many find they
are compensated by the freedom to make great fortunes selling
their services to the highest bidder.
					</p>
					<p>
					<b>Playing a Warcaster:</b> The Warcaster could perhaps best be
summarized by "limitless potential." Though the Warcaster
has only one archetype choice (Gifted) and relatively short skill
lists, the power of the Bond ability cannot be overstated and is
always a good choice for a Warcaster. Bonded warcaster armor
adds to a Warcaster's vitality and can be empowered to add to his
ARM as well. Bonded warcaster weapons can use focus points to
boost attack rolls, boost damage rolls, or even make additional
attacks, and bonded steamjacks are the most powerful weapons
in a party's arsenal. Virtually any other career can make a good
pairing for Warcaster. From the deadly Cutthroat-Warcaster to
the implacable Knight-Warcaster, almost nothing is off-limits.
					</p>
					<p>
					Experienced Warcasters want an extra selection or two of the
Bond ability, but they'll also want additional spells and abilities
from their other career. Veteran and Epic-level Warcasters
can also take field marshal abilities, granting their whole
battlegroup additional abilities.
					</p>
					
								
				</text>
			</warcaster>
			
			