
			
				<alchemicalorder>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.alchemicalorder@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Alchemical Order</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character can call upon the knowledge,
resources, and talents of an alchemical order, such as the Order
of the Golden Crucible. If the character is an alchemist, he is
likely a member of the order. A member of an order can, at very
least, expect access his order's labs and libraries and possibly
a bed and meal. His friends and other traveling companions
might not be as welcome.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</alchemicalorder>
				
				<criminal>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.criminal@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Criminal</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has contacts with the criminal
underworld and organized crime. His connections are
likely centered on a single city or criminal organization,
but those contacts can to reach out to other organizations
on the character's behalf. The character can always press his
contacts for information, and he might also be able to use
them to purchase or smuggle contraband, set up criminal
enterprises, aid in entering or escaping locations unseen,
dispose of goods or bodies, find safe hiding places, or for
anything else that falls under the criminal purview. Such
contacts are notoriously untrustworthy and complications
abound. Greed and self interest are the surest motivators
when dealing with these connections.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</criminal>
				
				<dwarvenclan>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.dwarvenclan@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Dwarven Clan</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has dealings with a dwarven
clan. Though a member of the clan can expect to be treated
like family, outsiders have a more business-like relationship
with the clan. The clan is likely based in Rhul, possibly with
smaller branches in Cygnar or Khador. The clan can provide
information, especially pertaining to trade routes, business
ventures, wartime developments, of news from Rhul. It can
also provide a great deal of technical expertise and other means
of support depending on the clan's holdings in the area where
they are encountered.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</dwarvenclan>
				
				<intelligencenetwork>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.intelligencenetwork@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Intelligence Network</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has access to a vast spy
network, such as the Cygnaran Reconnaissance Network, the
Prikaz Chancellery, the Unseen Hand, or the Retribution of
Scyrah. The character's relationship with the network should
be discussed between the player and the Game Master. If he is
a member of the group, the character can expect much greater
access to information and material aid, but he has substantial
responsibilities in return. He could be called upon the network
to provide information and assistance at any time. If he betrays
his organization or exposes its members, he will certainly be
marked for death. More informal affiliates of an organization
can be called upon for information and possibly support when
the network's aims coincide with the character's actions. Such
networks are proficient, professional, and ruthless. The spy
game is no place for amateurs.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</intelligencenetwork>
				
				<knightlyorder>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.knightlyorder@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Knightly Order</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has a connection to a knightly
order. He could be a member of the order or an advocate for
its causes. In either case, he can use this connection to gain
information pertaining to the affairs of the order, its members,
and its home kingdom. If the character is a member, he can
also call on the resources of his order and can find a warm
bed and a hot meal at his order's holdings. The character can
also expect to have armor repaired and his mount groomed.
From time to time, the character's order might call upon him
to undertake tasks relating to his responsibilities as a knight
of the order.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</knightlyorder>
				
				<kriel>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.kriel@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Kriel</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has contact with a trollkin kriel. He could
be a close friend or ally, or a member of the kriel. The kriel is
either based at a village or urban settlement, or nomadic. With
great numbers of trollkin having been uprooted by the recent
wars, there are greater numbers of nomadic trollkin than ever
before. The character can call upon the kriel for information
relating to trollkin history, its home history, and the individual
knowledge of the members of the tribe. Likely the kriel has little
in the way of material support it can lend a character, but the
kriel might provide warriors in times of need, especially if the
kriel shares the character's interests in a given fight. What little
the kriel has, it is likely to share with a friend. As a member of a
kriel, a character could be called upon to aid the kriel in its most
dire moments, especially if the character is a Fell Caller or has
another important role in his kriel.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</kriel>
				
				
				<magicalorder>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.magicalorder@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Magical Order (Arcanist or Gun Mage)</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character
is affiliated with an arcane order, such as the Greylords
Covenant, the Fraternal Order of Wizardry, or the Militant
Order of the Arcane Tempest. Many, but not all, orders are tied
very closely to a given kingdom and membership in the order
is limited to citizens of that kingdom in good standing. For
example, the Gun Mages of the Arcane Tempest are members
of Cygnar's military in addition to being members of the
order. A character with a connection to an arcane order can
call upon the order for information relating to the knowledge
of the order, its current dealings, information pertaining to
its members, and to its home kingdom. A character might
also be able to call upon the services of the order in times of
need. Members can expect to be welcomed into the order's
chapter houses, fed, given access to the chapter's facilities and
libraries, and possibly given a place to sleep.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</magicalorder>
				
				
				<mechaniksorganization>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.mechaniksorganization@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Mechaniks Organization</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has contact with a
major mechanik's organization or firm such as the Khadoran
Mechanik's Assembly, the Steam &amp; Iron Workers' Union,
Engines East, the Cygnaran Armory, or Black Anchor Heavy
Industries. The character can utilize this connection to gather
information pertaining to the organization, its projects, or its
members. Members of the organization can expect to recruited
for work, given access to machine shops, and possibly be able
to scrounge parts and scrap metal. Members of unions are
required to pay their dues.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</mechaniksorganization>
				
				<militarykingdomormercenary>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.militarykingdomormercenary@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Military, Kingdom or Mercenary</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has a
connection with a mercenary company or with one of the
kingdom's militaries. Most likely the character is or was a
member of that military. Though he maintains contacts with
the group, how he is perceived depends on his service record
and the terms on which he left duty. A character can call
upon his contacts to discover the details of given battles,
gain intelligence on troop movements, learn about an aspect
of the military, or gain access to its personnel. A character
might be able to leverage his connections to get his hands on
military gear or to request aid from former brothers in arms.
This sort of aid usually comes at a high cost. If the character
is an active member of the military, that complication adds
its own issues and is sure to curtail the character's mobility
and options for adventure.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</militarykingdomormercenary>
				
				<nobility>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.nobility@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Nobility</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has connections to the nobility of
a given kingdom or the members of a continent-spanning
dynastic family. The character might even be a lesser nobleman
in his own right. Whichever the case, the character has access
to the halls of power. He can use these contacts to learn the
secrets of the great families, the truths behind politics, or to
gain access to the most powerful men in western Immoren.
Such benefits are not without their cost. The nobility is vain,
self-interested, jaded, and value appearances above all else.
In addition to having to return favors, a character also has
to be on his best behavior to maintain noble connections. A
character who is crude, insulting, impolite, or impolitic can
expect his connections to wither and die. Not only do the
nobility not wish to aid an embarrassing ally, they do not wish
to seem to be aiding that ally.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</nobility>
				
				<piratecrew>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.piratecrew@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Pirate Crew</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character is either the member of a pirate
crew or has a close connection to a crew, likely through its
captain. The pirates can be called upon to provide information
pertaining to ports of call, the strength of various navies,
trade lanes, the best locations for plunder, hiding places along
the coast, and all manner of lore pertaining ships and piracy.
Pirates can be called up for transportation and possibly for help
in a fight if there is plunder for the taking. Just remember that
no one can trust a pirate.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</piratecrew>
				
				<retributionofscyrah>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.retributionofscyrah@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Retribution of Scyrah</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has access to a vast spy
network, such as the Cygnaran Reconnaissance Network, the
Prikaz Chancellery, the Unseen Hand, or the Retribution of
Scyrah. The character's relationship with the network should
be discussed between the player and the Game Master. If he is
a member of the group, the character can expect much greater
access to information and material aid, but he has substantial
responsibilities in return. He could be called upon the network
to provide information and assistance at any time. If he betrays
his organization or exposes its members, he will certainly be
marked for death. More informal affiliates of an organization
can be called upon for information and possibly support when
the network's aims coincide with the character's actions. Such
networks are proficient, professional, and ruthless. The spy
game is no place for amateurs.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</retributionofscyrah>
				
				<religiousorganization>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.religiousorganization@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Religious Organization</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has contact with one
of the major religions of western Immoren. If the character
is not a member of the church, this connection provides him
with information only. If he is a member of the church, he can
expect access to the organization's churches, libraries, and
other holdings, and he can gain access to ranking members of
the church. Should his actions be in the interests of the church,
he can potentially expect even greater aid in times of need. Of
course, should the character bring shame upon the church or
fail in its central teachings, he might find himself ostracized
and his access denied.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</religiousorganization>
				
				<wealthypatrons>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>ability</class>
							<recordname>reference.connections.index.wealthypatrons@Iron Kingdoms Core Rules</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Wealthy Patrons</name>
					<type type="string">Connection</type>					
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>
					The character has a network of wealthy
patrons that go out of their way to aid him in times of need. This
network is made up of aristocrats, industrialists, and men of
privilege who either believe in the character's work or see their
connection to the character as a means of winning acclaim and
sharing in his victories. The character can call upon his patrons
for information relating to politics and trade and can call upon
their financial support. The character's contacts expect to see a
return on their investments. The character's associates might be
willing to finance a dangerous sea voyage or treasure hunting
expedition to isolated ruins, but only if they expect the plan to
succeed. They might monitor the character's use of their money
and even send observers along on his expeditions. The character
is expected to give private and personal presentations regarding
his adventures and findings, any artifacts he discovers are put
on display for the pleasure of his patrons, and they take a stake
in any financial rewards that spring from their investments.
Additionally, the character's patrons expect him to maintain a
degree of decorum and professionalism that does not besmirch
their own reputations.
					</p>
					</benefit>
				</wealthypatrons>
				
			